2	O

EXPLANATORY	O
NOTICES	O
.	O

6	O

EXPLANATORY	O
NOTICES	O
.	O

Explanation	O
of	O
the	O
column	O
headed	O
“	O
Thermometrical	O
Register	O
.	O
"	O

The	O
Thermometrical	O
Register	O
commences	O
with	O
Nov	B-DATE
.	I-DATE
1853	I-DATE
,	O
and	O
closes	O
with	O
Oct	B-DATE
.	I-DATE
1854	I-DATE
,	O

inclusive	O
.	O
These	O
registers	O
have	O
been	O
carefully	O
copied	O
from	O
those	O
made	O
at	O
the	O
Royal	B-NORP

Observatory	I-NORP
,	O
Greenwich	B-GPE
,	O
and	O
which	O
are	O
also	O
deposited	O
with	O
the	B-NORP
Royal	I-NORP
Society	I-NORP
.	O
They	O

show	O
the	O
highest	O
and	O
lowest	O
ranges	O
within	O
each	O
twenty	O
-	O
four	O
hours	O
,	O
from	O
twelve	B-CARDINAL
different	O

readings	O
.	O
Each	O
month	O
is	O
placed	O
with	O
its	O
corresponding	O
month	O
,	O
as	O
affording	O
the	O
most	O

ready	O
and	O
advantageous	O
means	O
of	O
comparison	O
,	O
although	O
by	O
this	O
arrangement	O
the	O
register	O

of	O
the	O
last	O
two	O
months	O
of	O
1833	B-DATE
follows	O
the	O
ten	O
months	O
of	O
1854	B-DATE
,	O
which	O
are	O
all	O
we	O
can	O
give	O

up	O
to	O
the	O
day	O
of	O
publication	B-PRODUCT
.	O

Explanation	O
of	O
the	O
columns	O
headed	O
“	O
Length	O
of	O
day	O
.	O
”	O
“	O
Day	O
's	O
increase	O
or	O
decrease	O
,	O
"	O

“	O
Day	O
breaks	O
,	O
”	O
and	O
“	O
Twilight	O
ends	O
.	O
"	O

The	O
column	O
headed	O
“	O
Length	O
of	O
day	O
”	O
contains	O
the	O
number	O
of	O
hours	O
and	O
minutes	O

between	O
sunrise	O
and	O
sunset	O
.	O
The	O
column	O
headed	O
“	O
Day	O
's	O
increase	O

expresses	O
the	O

number	O
of	O
hours	O
and	O
minutes	O
which	O
the	O
day	O
has	O
increased	O
since	O
the	O
shortest	O
day	O
;	O
and	O
,	O

where	O
the	O
column	O
is	O
headed	O
“	O
Day	O
's	O
decrease	O
,	O
”	O
it	O
expresses	O
the	O
number	O
of	O
hours	O
and	O

minutes	O
which	O
the	O
day	O
has	O
decreased	O
since	O
the	O
longest	O
day	O
;	O
for	O
example	O
,	O
the	O
length	O
of	O

the	O
longest	O
day	O
in	O
1853	B-DATE
is	O
put	O
down	O
in	O
the	O
column	O
“	O
Length	O
of	O
day	O
"	O
at	O
16	B-TIME
h	I-TIME
.	I-TIME
34	I-TIME
m	I-TIME
.	O
;	O

and	O
on	O
the	O
6th	B-DATE
of	I-DATE
July	I-DATE
following	O
we	O
find	O
that	O
the	O
length	O
of	O
the	O
day	O
,	O
or	O
the	O
number	O
of	O

hours	O
and	O
minutes	O
between	O
sunrise	O
and	O
sunset	O
,	O
is	O
set	O
down	O
at	O
16	B-TIME
h	I-TIME
.	I-TIME
24	I-TIME
m	I-TIME
.	O
;	O
hence	O
the	O

day	O
has	O
decreased	O
10	B-TIME
m	I-TIME
.	O
since	O
the	O
longest	O
day	O
,	O
and	O
,	O
accordingly	O
,	O
in	O
the	O
column	O
“	O
Day	O
's	O

decrease	O
,	O
”	O
we	O
find	O
opposite	O
July	B-DATE
the	I-DATE
6th	I-DATE
Oh	O
.	O
10	B-TIME
m	I-TIME
.	O

Equation	O
of	O
Time	O
.	O

In	O
this	O
Almanac	B-PRODUCT
the	O
calculations	O
are	O
all	O
made	O
for	O
mean	O
time	O
(	O
given	O
by	O
the	O
clock	O
)	O
,	O

instead	O
of	O
apparent	O
time	O
(	O
given	O
by	O
the	O
sun	O
-	O
dial	O
)	O
,	O
which	O
latter	O
had	O
been	O
used	O
up	O
to	O
the	O

It	O
must	O
be	O
obvious	O
that	O
,	O
for	O
all	O
practical	O
purposes	O
,	O
mean	O
time	O
is	O
the	O
most	O

useful	O
;	O
and	O
to	O
obtain	O
it	O
from	O
apparent	O
time	O
,	O
the	O
columns	O
in	O
the	O
Almanac	B-PRODUCT
headed	O

Equation	O
of	O
Time	O
"	O
should	O
be	O
used	O
.	O
The	O
column	O
“	O
Equation	O
of	O
Time	O
"	O
ought	O
,	O
for	O

example	O
,	O
to	O
be	O
consulted	O
when	O
persons	O
are	O
desirous	O
of	O
setting	O
their	O
clock	O
by	O
a	O
sun	O
-	O
dial	O
.	O

When	O
clock	O
after	O
sun	O
is	O
written	O
above	O
the	O
number	O
of	O
minutes	O
and	O
seconds	O
opposite	O
to	O
the	O

day	O
,	O
then	O
the	O
clock	O
ought	O
to	O
be	O
set	O
so	O
much	O
slower	O
than	O
the	O
sun	O
-	O
dial	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
contrary	O
.	O

Moonlight	O
.	O

Tue	O
Moon	O
's	O
age	O
is	O
set	O
down	O
in	O
days	O
and	O
the	O
nearest	O
tenths	O
of	O
days	O
from	O
the	O
time	O
of	O

change	O
.	O
Thus	O
it	O
is	O
New	O
Moon	O
on	O
the	O
16th	B-DATE
of	I-DATE
February	I-DATE
at	O
6	B-TIME
h	I-TIME
.	I-TIME
47	I-TIME
m	I-TIME
.	O
afternoon	O
,	O
and	O
there	O
.	O

fore	O
at	O
noon	O
on	O
the	B-DATE
17th	I-DATE
she	O
is	O
17	B-TIME
h	I-TIME
.	I-TIME
23	I-TIME
m	I-TIME
.	O
old	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
set	O
down	O
as	O
seven	O
-	O
tenths	O
.	O
The	O

fraction	O
of	O
the	O
day	O
of	O
course	O
continues	O
the	O
same	O
throughout	O
the	O
lunation	O
.	O

year	O
1833	B-DATE
.	O

1	O

LIST	O
OF	O
THE	O
CORRESPONDENCE	O
OF	O
ERAS	O
WITH	O
THE	O
YEAR	O
1855	B-DATE
.	O

[	O
In	O
those	O
Eras	O
which	O
begin	O
with	O
the	O
Christian	O
year	O
,	O
the	O
year	O
alone	O
is	O
stated	O
;	O
in	O
those	O

which	O
begin	O
at	O
a	O
different	O
season	O
,	O
the	O
month	O
in	O
which	O
the	O
1st	O
of	O
January	B-DATE
,	I-DATE
1855	I-DATE
,	O
occurs	O

is	O
also	O
given	O
.	O
]	O

Correspondence	O
Abbre	O
-	O

with	O
1855	B-DATE
.	O
viations	O
,	O

Roman	B-DATE
Year	I-DATE

2608	I-DATE
A	O
.	O
U	O
.	O
C	O
.	O

Year	O
of	O
the	O
World	O
(	O
Constantinopolitan	O
account	O
)	O

736	O
3 A.M.	O
Const	O
.	O

Ditto	O
(	O
Alexandrian	O
account	O
)	O

7	B-DATE
347 A.M.	I-DATE
Alex	O
.	O

Ditto	O
(	O
Jewish	O
account	O
)	O
.	O
.	O

Ilth	O
Thebet	O
5	O
615 A.M.	B-TIME

Era	O
of	O
Nabonassar	O

8th	B-DATE
Pharmuti	I-DATE
2603	I-DATE
Ær	I-DATE
.	I-DATE
Nab	I-DATE
.	I-DATE

Egyptian	O

.	O
.	O
.	O
24th	B-DATE
Cohiac	I-DATE
2601	I-DATE
A	I-DATE
.	I-DATE
Æg	I-DATE
.	I-DATE

Julian	O
Period	O

6568	B-DATE

Jul	O
.	O
Per	O
.	O

Dioclesian	O
,	O
or	O
of	O
Martyrs	O

24th	B-DATE
Cohiac	I-DATE
1571	I-DATE
Ær	I-DATE
.	O
Diocl	O
.	O

Seleucides	O
,	O
or	O
Grecian	O

Audynæus	O
2166	O
Ær	O
.	O
Seleuc	O
.	O

Death	O
of	O
Alexander	B-PERSON	B-GPE

3	O
d	O
month	O
of	O
2178	O
A	O
.	O
Mor	O
.	O
Alex	O
.	O

Era	O
of	O
Tyre	B-GPE

.	O
.	O
.	O
.	O
.	O
Audynæus	O
1979	O
Ær	O
.	O
Tyr	O
.	O

Cæsarian	O
of	O
Antioch	B-PERSON
(	O
Greek	O
)	O

.	O
.	O
.	O
.	O
.	O
.	O
.	O
.	O
.	O
.	O
.	O
Audynæus	O
1903	O
Cæs	O
.	O
Ant	O
.	O

Ditto	O
(	O
Syrian	O
)	O

Canun	O
II	O
.	O
1902	B-DATE

Era	O
of	O
Abraham	B-PERSON

4th	O
month	O
of	O
3870	B-DATE
Ær	I-DATE
.	O
Abr	O
.	O

Spanish	O
,	O
or	O
of	O
the	O
Cæsars	O

1893	B-DATE
A	I-DATE
.	I-DATE
Cæs	I-DATE
.	O

Persian	B-DATE
Era	I-DATE
of	I-DATE
Yezdegird	I-DATE
III	I-DATE
.	I-DATE
(	I-DATE
Parsee	I-DATE
account	I-DATE
)	I-DATE

1224	I-DATE
A	I-DATE
.	I-DATE
Pers	I-DATE
.	I-DATE

Armenian	O
common	O
year	O
.	O
.	O
.	O
.	O

.	O
.	O
5th	B-DATE
Kaghots	I-DATE
1304	I-DATE
An	I-DATE
.	I-DATE
Arm	I-DATE
.	I-DATE

Ditto	O
ecclesiastical	O
year	O

12th	B-DATE
Kagnots	I-DATE
1303	I-DATE

Hegira	O
.	O
.	O
.	O
.	O

Ist	O
Rabiu	O
II	O
.	O
1271	O

Α	O
.	O
Η	O
.	O

Kaliyug	O
.	O
.	O

Poos	B-DATE
or	I-DATE
Margaly	I-DATE
4956	I-DATE
Cal	I-DATE
.	O

Salivahana	O

Ditto	O

1777	O
Saca	O
.	O

Vikramaditya	O

Ditto	O
1911	O
Samvat	O
.	O

#	O
#	O
p	O
.	O
5	O
(	O
#	O
105	O
)	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O

COMPANION	O
TO	O
THE	O
ALMANAC	B-PRODUCT

FOR	O

1855	B-DATE
.	O

PART	O
I	O
.	O

GENERAL	O
INFORMATION	O
ON	O
SUBJECTS	O
OF	O
MATHEMATICS	O
,	O

NATURAL	O
PHILOSOPHY	O
AND	O
HISTORY	O
,	O
CHRONOLOGY	O
,	O

GEOGRAPHY	O
,	O
STATISTICS	O
,	O
&	O
c	O
.	O

I	O
.	O
THE	O
PROGRESS	O
OF	O
THE	O
DOCTRINE	O
OF	O
THE	O

EARTH	O
'S	O
MOTION	O
,	O
BETWEEN	O
THE	O
TIMES	O
OF	O
CO	B-PERSON
-	I-PERSON

PERNICUS	I-PERSON
AND	O
GALILEO	B-PERSON
;	O
BEING	O
NOTES	O
ON	O
THE	O

ANTEGALILEAN	O
COPERNICANS	O
.	O

Any	O
reader	O
of	O
the	O
common	O
accounts	O
of	O
astronomical	O
history	O
might	O

suppose	O
that	O
the	O
moment	O
Copernicus	B-PERSON
sowed	O
the	O
dragon	O
's	O
teeth	O
,	O
a	O

host	O
of	O
armed	O
controversialists	O
arose	O
from	O
out	O
of	O
the	O
ground	O
,	O
and	O

proceeded	O
to	O
mutual	O
slaughter	O
.	O
This	O
arises	O
from	O
the	O
manner	O
in	O

which	O
popular	O
writers	O
are	O
naturally	O
led	O
to	O
pass	O
over	O
an	O
intervening	O

time	O
,	O
and	O
to	O
bring	O
their	O
readers	O
at	O
once	O
to	O
the	O
story	O
of	O
Galileo	O
and	O

the	B-EVENT
Inquisition	I-EVENT
.	O
But	O
when	O
it	O
is	O
remembered	O
that	O
this	O
period	O
of	O
ex	O
.	O

citement	O
begins	O
with	O
the	O
construction	O
of	O
the	O
telescope	O
in	O
1609	B-DATE
,	O
and	O

that	O
the	O
work	O
of	O
Copernicus	B-PERSON
was	O
published	O
in	O
1543	B-DATE
,	O
it	O
will	O
appear	O

that	O
there	O
is	O
a	O
term	O
of	O
no	O
less	O
than	O
66	O
years	O
during	O
which	O
the	O
pro	O
-	O

gress	O
of	O
opinion	O
is	O
to	O
be	O
accounted	O
for	O
.	O
That	O
is	O
,	O
the	O
contemporaries	O

of	O
Galileo	B-PERSON
looked	O
back	O
upon	O
the	O
announcement	O
of	O
the	O
motion	O
of	O
the	O

earth	O
just	O
as	O
we	O
look	O
back	O
upon	O
the	O
commencement	O
of	O
the	O
first	O

French	B-EVENT
revolution	I-EVENT
.	O

During	O
this	O
term	O
of	O
66	O
years	O
,	O
the	O
question	O
was	O
not	O
,	O
properly	O
speak	O
-	O

ing	O
,	O
discussed	O
.	O
Various	O
writers	O
gave	O
opinions	O
,	O
but	O
no	O
book	O
was	O

written	O
against	O
another	O
book	O
.	O
Some	O
leaned	O
towards	O
the	O
actual	O

motion	O
of	O
the	O
earth	B-LOC
:	O
some	O
got	O
no	O
further	O
than	O
the	O
armission	O
of	O
that	O

motion	O
as	O
a	O
very	O
simple	O
anii	O
efficacious	O
way	O
of	O
deducing	O
the	O
plane	O
-	O

tary	O
motions	O
.	O
Some	O
thought	O
that	O
the	O
diurnal	O
motion	O
only	O
could	O
be	O

maintained	O
:	O
others	O
were	O
equally	O
in	O
favour	O
of	O
the	O
motion	O
round	O
the	O

The	O
difference	O
between	O
a	O
physical	O
and	O
a	O
mathematical	O
use	O
of	O
the	O

Copernican	O
or	O
any	O
other	O
theory	O
,	O
is	O
one	O
which	O
is	O
rather	O
puzzling	O
to	O
a	O

reader	O
unaccustomed	O
to	O
such	O
considerations	O
.	O
A	O
mathematical	O

Copernican	O
was	O
one	O
who	O
saw	O
that	O
,	O
come	O
how	O
it	O
might	O
,	O
the	O
heavenly	O

appearances	O
are	O
such	O
as	O
would	O
take	O
place	O
if	O
the	O
earth	B-LOC
did	O
move	O
about	O

the	O
sun	O
,	O
and	O
also	O
about	O
its	O
own	O
axis	O
:	O
and	O
that	O
,	O
consequently	O
,	O
the	O

sun	O
.	O

#	O
#	O
p	O
.	O
6	O
(	O
#	O
106	O
)	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O

6	O

Notes	O
on	O
the	O
Antegalilean	O
Copernicans	B-ORG
.	O

supposition	O
of	O
such	O
motions	O
,	O
true	O
or	O
false	O
,	O
would	O
be	O
a	O
convenient	O
and	O

efficacious	O
mode	O
of	O
explaining	O
and	O
predicting	O
celestial	O
phenomena	O
.	O

A	O
physical	O
Copernican	O
added	O
to	O
the	O
above	O
the	O
belief	O
that	O
the	O
reason	O

why	O
things	O
appear	O
as	O
they	O
would	O
if	O
the	O
earth	O
had	O
these	O
motions	O
,	O
is	O

that	O
it	O
really	O
has	O
them	O
.	O
The	O
first	O
said	O
that	O
the	O
hypothesis	O
explains	O

or	O
demonstrates	O
phenomena	O
;	O
the	O
second	O
said	O
that	O
the	O
hypothesis	O
is	O
a	O

true	O
statement	O
of	O
the	O
causes	O
which	O
produce	O
phenomena	O
.	O

Every	O
person	O
who	O
knows	O
the	O
heavenly	O
motions	O
,	O
as	O
they	O
appear	O

before	O
our	O
eyes	O
,	O
and	O
has	O
a	O
little	O
knowledge	O
of	O
geometry	O
,	O
must	O
be	O
a	O

mathematical	O
Copernican	O
:	O
he	O
cannot	O
fail	O
to	O
see	O
that	O
a	O
Copernican	O

universe	O
would	O
show	O
the	O
same	O
appearances	O
as	O
that	O
in	O
which	O
we	O
live	O
.	O

Accordingly	O
,	O
from	O
the	O
moment	O
when	O
the	O
work	O
of	O
Copernicus	O
ap	O
-	O

peared	O
,	O
the	O
beauty	O
of	O
the	O
explanation	O
was	O
fully	O
acknowledged	O
,	O
and	O

the	O
author	O
took	O
his	O
place	O
at	O
once	O
among	O
mathematicians	B-ORG
of	O
the	O
first	O

order	O
,	O
both	O
for	O
his	O
own	O
novelties	O
,	O
and	O
for	O
his	O
additions	O
to	O
the	O
old	O

system	O
.	O
The	O
highest	O
terms	O
of	O
praise	O
are	O
found	O
in	O
the	O
writings	O
of	O

those	O
who	O
were	O
most	O
opposed	O
to	O
the	O
physical	O
truth	O
of	O
the	O
hypothesis	O
.	O

Those	O
who	O
were	O
inclined	O
to	O
blame	O
the	O
novelty	O
of	O
the	O
system	O
-	O
for	O
in	O

every	O
age	O
the	O
production	O
of	O
new	O
opinions	O
meets	O
with	O
reproach	O
-	O
had	O

their	O
mouths	O
stopped	O
by	O
reference	O
to	O
those	O
among	O
the	O
ancients	O
who	O

were	O
known	O
to	O
have	O
believed	O
the	O
actual	O
motion	O
of	O
the	O
earth	O
.	O

It	O
is	O
said	O
that	O
Leonardo	B-PERSON
da	I-PERSON
Vinci	I-PERSON
held	O
the	O
motion	O
of	O
the	O
earth	B-LOC
,	O
as	O

appears	O
by	O
his	O
manuscripts	O
,	O
about	O
1500	B-DATE
:	O
but	O
it	O
does	O
not	O
appear	O
that	O

he	O
constructed	O
any	O
system	O
of	O
explanations	O
.	O
There	O
was	O
a	O
work	O
of	O

Calcagnini	B-PERSON
actually	O
written	O
and	O
made	O
known	O
(	O
divolgo	O
,	O
says	O
Tiraboschi	B-PERSON
,	O

which	O
we	O
suppose	O
does	O
not	O
imply	O
printing	O
)	O
before	O
that	O
of	O
Copernicus	B-PERSON
,	O

in	O
which	O
the	O
earth	O
's	O
motion	O
was	O
defended	O
:	O
but	O
as	O
the	O
author	O
was	O

known	O
to	O
have	O
travelled	O
in	O
Poland	B-GPE
,	O
where	O
Copernicus	B-PERSON
had	O
long	O
been	O

teaching	O
his	O
system	O
in	O
every	O
way	O
except	O
through	O
the	O
press	O
,	O
as	O
well	O

as	O
for	O
other	O
reasons	O
,	O
the	O
Italians	B-NORP
suppose	O
he	O
must	O
have	O
had	O
know	O
-	O

ledge	O
of	O
Copernicus	B-PERSON
and	O
his	O
opinions	O
.	O
In	O
1533	B-DATE
,	O
J	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Albert	I-PERSON
Widman	I-PERSON
-	I-PERSON

stadt	I-PERSON
,	O
afterwards	O
known	O
as	O
an	O
oriental	O
scholar	O
,	O
explained	O
the	O
views	O
of	O

Copernicus	B-PERSON
before	O
Clement	B-PERSON
VII	I-PERSON
.	O
,	O
for	O
which	O
explanation	O
that	O
Pope	B-PERSON

presented	O
him	O
with	O
a	O
Greek	O
manuscript	O
,	O
which	O
was	O
preserved	O
at	O

Monaco	B-GPE
in	O
the	O
last	O
century	O
with	O
an	O
inscription	O
by	O
Widmanstadt	B-PERSON

recording	O
the	O
gift	O
and	O
the	O
reason	O
.	O

We	O
shall	O
now	O
give	O
some	O
detached	O
accounts	O
of	O
the	O
mode	O
in	O
which	O

the	O
system	O
presented	O
itself	O
to	O
those	O
whom	O
we	O
may	O
term	O
its	O
Antega	O
-	O

lilean	O
supporters	O
or	O
opponents	O
.	O
The	O
dates	O
attached	O
are	O
those	O
of	O

death	O
,	O
but	O
all	O
the	O
writers	O
belong	O
to	O
the	O
sixteenth	O
century	O
.	O

Nicholas	B-PERSON
Copernicus	I-PERSON
(	O
1543	B-DATE
)	O
.	O
—	O
The	O
question	O
whether	O
Copernicus	B-PERSON

himself	O
was	O
a	O
Copernican	O
in	O
the	O
modern	O
sense	O
of	O
the	O
word	O
is	O
not	O

easily	O
settled	O
.	O
His	O
phraseology	O
is	O
almost	O
always	O
that	O
of	O
a	O
mathema	O
-	O

tical	O
Copernican	O
(	O
Comp	O
.	O
Alm	O
.	O
1853	B-DATE
,	O
p	O
.	O
9	B-CARDINAL
,	O
note	O
8	B-CARDINAL
)	O
.	O
In	O
a	O
very	O
few	O

places	O
,	O
and	O
cautiously	O
,	O
he	O
leans	O
to	O
the	O
physical	O
truth	O
as	O
probable	O
,	O

and	O
to	O
the	O
diurnal	O
motion	O
as	O
more	O
probable	O
than	O
the	O
orbital	O
.	O
When	O

the	O
Congregation	B-NORP
of	I-NORP
the	I-NORP
Index	I-NORP
,	O
in	O
1620	B-DATE
,	O
propounded	O
the	O
alterations	O

under	O
which	O
they	O
could	O
allow	O
his	O
book	O
to	O
be	O
read	O
as	O
a	O
mathematical	O

hypothesis	O
,	O
they	O
found	O
those	O
alterations	O
very	O
few	O
in	O
number	O
:	O
and	O
,	O

though	O
confessedly	O
disposed	O
to	O
cancel	O
the	O
whole	O
of	O
Chapter	O
VIII	O
.	O
,	O

as	O
treating	O
of	O
the	O
truth	O
of	O
the	O
motion	O
of	O
the	O
earth	B-LOC
,	O
they	O
were	O
never	O
-	O

a	O

#	O
#	O
p	O
.	O
7	O
(	O
#	O
107	O
)	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O

Notes	O
on	O
the	O
Antegalilean	B-ORG
Copernicans	I-ORG
.	O

7	O

theless	O
able	O
to	O
allow	O
it	O
to	O
stand	O
,	O
because	O
the	O
author	O
seemed	O
to	O
be	O

speaking	O
problematically	O
;	O
whence	O
they	O
only	O
imposed	O
a	O
few	O
verbal	O
al	O
-	O

terations	O
.	O
Riccioli	B-PERSON
(	O
Alm	O
.	O
N	O
.	O
ii	O
.	O
294	O
)	O
affirms	O
Copernicus	B-PERSON
to	O
have	O
been	O

a	O
physical	O
*	O
Copernican	O
,	O
and	O
cites	O
the	O
passages	O
which	O
,	O
in	O
his	O
opinion	O
,	O

prove	O
it	O
;	O
but	O
he	O
does	O
not	O
feel	O
able	O
to	O
get	O
farther	O
than	O
the	O
qualified	O

statement	O
that	O
Copernicus	B-PERSON
maintained	O
the	O
motion	O
of	O
the	O
earth	B-LOC
as	O

more	O
probable	O
,	O
or	O
even	O
as	O
demonstrated	O
.	O
The	O
reader	O
who	O
can	O
com	O
-	O

pare	O
the	O
passages	O
in	O
the	O
page	O
cited	O
with	O
the	O
alterations	O
demanded	O
by	O

the	O
Congregation	B-NORP
in	O
p	O
.	O
496	B-DATE
,	O
will	O
be	O
able	O
to	O
judge	O
for	O
himself	O
:	O
see	O

also	O
the	O
life	O
of	O
Copernicus	B-PERSON
in	O
the	O
Penny	B-PRODUCT
Cyclopædia	I-PRODUCT
.	O

George	B-PERSON
Joachim	I-PERSON
Rheticus	I-PERSON
(	O
1576	B-DATE
)	O
.	O
-	O
-	O
This	O
celebrated	O
friend	O
of	O

Copernicus	B-PERSON
,	O
and	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
principal	O
instigators	O
of	O
his	O
publication	B-PRODUCT
,	O

was	O
himself	O
the	O
first	O
announcer	O
of	O
the	O
forthcoming	O
system	O
,	O
in	O
his	O

Narratio	O
,	O
&	O
c	O
.	O
,	O
published	O
in	O
1540	B-DATE
_	O
(	O
Comp	O
.	O
1853	B-DATE
,	O
p	O
.	O
9	O
)	O
.	O
It	O
may	O
be	O

collected	O
from	O
this	O
letter	O
that	O
Rheticus	B-PERSON
was	O
,	O
more	O
than	O
Coper	B-PERSON
-	I-PERSON

nicus	I-PERSON
,	O
inclined	O
to	O
express	O
his	O
belief	O
in	O
the	O
motion	O
of	O
the	O
earth	B-LOC
as	O

an	O
absolute	O
truth	O
.	O
But	O
the	O
passages	O
which	O
prove	O
this	O
are	O
im	O
-	O

bedded	O
in	O
accounts	O
of	O
the	O
manner	O
in	O
which	O
the	O
system	O
explains	O

phenomena	O
,	O
and	O
it	O
would	O
take	O
more	O
space	O
than	O
we	O
can	O
give	O
to	O
put	O

in	O
evidencet	O
the	O
distinction	O
between	O
the	O
phrases	O
of	O
Copernicus	B-PERSON
and	O

those	O
of	O
his	O
herald	O
.	O
The	O
following	O
paragraph	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
will	O
show	O

the	O
manner	O
in	O
which	O
the	O
account	O
struck	O
another	O
person	O
.	O

Achilles	B-PERSON
Gassarus	I-PERSON
.	O
—	O
His	O
letter	O
(	O
Comp	O
.	O
Alm	O
.	O
1853	B-DATE
,	O
p	O
.	O
9	B-CARDINAL
,	O
note	O
*	O
)	O
,	O

written	O
in	O
1540	B-DATE
,	O
upon	O
receipt	O
of	O
a	O
copy	O
of	O
the	O
Narratio	O
from	O
his	O

friend	O
Rheticus	B-PERSON
accompanied	O
by	O
a	O
very	O
full	O
private	O
letter	O
,	O
epistola	O

harum	O
rerum	O
refertissima	O
,	O
was	O
printed	O
at	O
the	O
head	O
of	O
the	O
edition	O
of	O

the	O
Narratio	O
referred	O
to	O
in	O
the	O
note	O
just	O
cited	O
.	O
No	O
doubt	O
this	O

private	O
letter	O
gave	O
very	O
explicit	O
statement	O
of	O
the	O
view	O
actually	O
taken	O

by	O
Rheticus	O
.	O
Delambre	O
(	O
Astr	O
.	O
Mod	O
.	O
vol	O
.	O
i	O
.	O
p	O
.	O
138	B-CARDINAL
)	O
imagines	O
that	O

it	O
was	O
the	O
work	O
of	O
Copernicus	B-PERSON
himself	O
which	O
was	O
sent	O
to	O
Gassarus	B-PERSON
;	O

and	O
concludes	O
,	O
from	O
copies	O
being	O
thus	O
issued	O
three	O
years	O
before	O
the	O

date	O
of	O
the	O
book	O
,	O
that	O
Copernicus	B-PERSON
delayed	O
its	O
publication	O
even	O

after	O
it	O
was	O
printed	O
.	O
But	O
this	O
is	O
a	O
mistake	O
:	O
we	O
know	O
perfectly	O
well	O

that	O
Copernicus	B-PERSON
never	O
opened	O
his	O
own	O
book	O
,	O
and	O
received	O
the	O
only	O

copy	O
he	O
ever	O
saw	O
on	O
the	O
very	O
day	O
of	O
his	O
death	O
.	O
Gassarus	B-PERSON
describes	O

the	O
publication	O
of	O
Rheticus	B-PERSON
as	O
of	O
novelty	O
enough	O
to	O
stupefy	O
any	O

one	O
,	O
as	O
most	O
contrary	O
to	O
the	O
doctrines	O
of	O
the	O
schools	O
,	O
and	O
as	O
what	O
the	O

monks	O
would	O
certainly	O
call	O
heretical	O
.	O
He	O
instances	O
the	O
motion	O
of	O

the	O
earth	O
as	O
among	O
the	O
wonders	O
,	O
but	O
enters	O
into	O
no	O
detail	O
,	O
apparently	O

because	O
he	O
sends	O
on	O
the	O
work	O
itself	O
to	O
his	O
correspondent	O
.	O
We	O
infer	O
,	O

then	O
,	O
that	O
Rheticus	B-PERSON
was	O
a	O
physical	O
Copernican	O
.	O
This	O
Gassarus	B-PERSON
was	O

the	O
constructor	O
of	O
a	O
series	O
of	O
almanacs	O
,	O
under	O
the	O
title	O
of	O
Prognosticon	O

a	O

a	O

*	O
All	O
the	O
writers	O
who	O
make	O
a	O
similar	O
affirmation	O
in	O
the	O
sixteenth	B-DATE
century	I-DATE
are	O
op	O
-	O

ponents	O
,	O
except	O
only	O
Thomas	B-PERSON
Digges	I-PERSON
,	O
who	O
stoutly	O
and	O
expressly	O
denies	O
(	O
in	O
1594	B-LOC
)	O
that	O

Copernicus	B-PERSON
meant	O
his	O
assertions	O
“	O
onely	O
as	O
mathematical	O
principles	O
fayned	O
,	O
and	O
not	O
as	O

philosophicall	O
truely	O
averred	O
.	O
”	O

+	O
Some	O
give	O
a	O
very	O
different	O
account	O
.	O
In	O
the	O
Penny	B-PRODUCT
Cyclopædia	I-PRODUCT
(	O
Rheticus	B-PERSON
)	O
,	O
ap	O
-	O

parently	O
after	O
Zedler	O
,	O
it	O
is	O
stated	O
that	O
this	O
Narratio	O
is	O
ahsolutely	O
written	O
in	O
opposition	O

to	O
Copernicus	B-PERSON
,	O
"	O
to	O
show	O
that	O
the	O
rotation	O
of	O
the	O
earth	O
about	O
the	O
sun	O
is	O
not	O
a	O
mere	O

probable	O
hypothesis	O
,	O
as	O
Copernicus	B-PERSON
had	O
thought	O
fit	O
to	O
announce	O
it	O
,	O
but	O
an	O
incontestable	O

truth	O
.	O
"	O

And	O
many	O
writers	O
,	O
though	O
not	O
going	O
so	O
far	O
as	O
this	O
,	O
are	O
yet	O
decided	O
in	O
their	O

statements	O
that	O
Rheticus	O
was	O
a	O
physical	O
Copernican	O
,	O
We	O
arrive	O
at	O
the	O
same	O
opinion	O

with	O
more	O
difficulty	O
.	O

#	O
#	O
p	O
.	O
8	O
(	O
#	O
108	O
)	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O

8	O

Notes	O
on	O
the	O
Antegalilean	B-ORG
Copernicans	I-ORG
.	O

Astrologicum	O
.	O
That	O
for	O
1546	B-DATE
is	O
dedicated	O
to	O
Rheticus	B-PERSON
,	O
who	O
,	O
says	O

Gassarus	B-PERSON
,	O
after	O
the	O
example	O
of	O
his	O
master	O
Copernicus	B-PERSON
,	O
gave	O
easier	O

introduction	O
and	O
clearer	O
demonstration	O
to	O
the	O
celestial	O
motions	O
.	O
It	O

is	O
probable	O
enough	O
that	O
,	O
next	O
afier	O
Rheticus	B-PERSON
,	O
Gassarus	B-PERSON
was	O
the	O
first	O

who	O
ventilated	O
the	O
name	O
of	O
Copernicus	B-PERSON
in	O
print	O
.	O

Erasmus	B-PERSON
Rheinhold	I-PERSON
(	O
1553	B-DATE
)	O
.	O
—	O
He	O
was	O
the	O
friend	O
of	O
Copernicus	B-PERSON
,	O

and	O
an	O
abettor	O
of	O
the	O
publication	O
;	O
but	O
his	O
view	O
was	O
very	O
different	O

from	O
that	O
of	O
Rheticus	B-PERSON
.	O
In	O
his	O
Prutenic	O
(	O
Prussian	O
)	O
tables	O
,	O
he	O
makes	O

use	O
of	O
the	O
observations	O
of	O
Copernicus	B-PERSON
,	O
and	O
he	O
constructs	O
tables	O
of	O
the	O

planets	O
both	O
on	O
the	O
old	O
and	O
on	O
the	O
Copernican	O
data	O
.	O
He	O
enters	O
into	O
no	O

discussion	O
,	O
and	O
(	O
according	O
to	O
Delambre	B-PERSON
)	O
finds	O
no	O
occasion	O
to	O
speak	O

either	O
of	O
the	O
motion	O
of	O
the	O
earth	O
or	O
of	O
the	O
sun	O
.	O
It	O
must	O
be	O
remarked	O

that	O
several	O
of	O
the	O
early	O
Copernicans	B-ORG
,	O
whatever	O
they	O
might	O
think	O
of	O

the	O
system	O
physically	O
or	O
mathematically	O
,	O
found	O
their	O
chief	O
source	O
of	O

admiration	O
in	O
the	O
changes	O
which	O
Copernicus	B-PERSON
made	O
in	O
the	O
numerical	O

data	O
of	O
the	O
planetary	O
,	O
and	O
especially	O
of	O
the	O
lunar	O
,	O
theory	O
.	O
These	O

numerical	O
data	O
might	O
with	O
ease	O
have	O
been	O
transplanted	O
into	O
the	O
Pto	O
-	O

lemaic	O
system	O
.	O
Rheinhold	B-PERSON
,	O
then	O
,	O
so	O
far	O
as	O
he	O
declares	O
himself	O
,	O
heads	O

the	O
school	O
of	O
numericai	O
Copernicans	B-ORG
.	O

Peter	B-orgperson
Ramus	I-orgperson
(	O
1572	B-DATE
)	O
.	O
—	O
This	O
celebrated	O
leader	O
of	O
opinion	O
is	O

reckoned	O
rather	O
among	O
the	O
philosophers	O
than	O
the	O
mathematicians	O
.	O

In	O
the	O
common	O
language	O
of	O
our	O
day	O
,	O
those	O
who	O
investigate	O
matter	O

have	O
usurped	O
the	O
name	O
of	O
philosopher	O
,	O
or	O
rather	O
,	O
perhaps	O
,	O
have	O
had	O

it	O
usurped	O
for	O
them	O
;	O
while	O
those	O
who	O
were	O
once	O
called	O
philo	O
-	O

sophers	O
*	O
are	O
now	O
usually	O
called	O
metaphysicians	O
.	O

This	O
is	O
of	O
no	O
con	O
-	O

sequence	O
,	O
t	O
except	O
in	O
the	O
confusion	O
it	O
creates	O
:	O
we	O
shall	O
in	O
this	O

article	O
use	O
the	O
term	O
philosopher	O
in	O
its	O
old	O
sense	O
.	O
Ramus	B-PERSON
,	O
a	O
thorough	O

opponent	O
of	O
the	O
old	O
philosophy	O
,	O
began	O
life	O
,	O
when	O
he	O
disputed	O
at	O
Paris	B-GPE

for	O
his	O
degree	O
of	O
master	O
of	O
arts	O
,	O
by	O
offering	O
to	O
maintain	O
the	O
contrary	O

of	O
any	O
assertion	O
whatsoever	O
of	O
Aristotle	B-PERSON
.	O
His	O
writings	O
†	O
were	O
censured	O

by	O
the	O
University	B-FAC
of	I-FAC
Paris	I-FAC	B-ORG
in	O
1543	B-DATE
,	O
the	O
year	O
in	O
which	O
Copernicus	B-PERSON

published	O
his	O
great	O
work	O
.	O
He	O
was	O
a	O
correspondent	O
of	O
Rheticus	B-PERSON
,	O
and	O

states	O
(	O
Sch	O
,	O
Math	O
.	O
book	O
ii	O
.	O
)	O
that	O
he	O
endeavoured	O
by	O
letter	O
to	O
per	O
-	O

suade	O
him	O
to	O
free	O
astronomy	O
altogether	O
from	O
hypothesis	O
;	O
and	O
that	O
if	O

Rheticus	B-PERSON
had	O
not	O
been	O
obliged	O
by	O
circumstances	O
to	O
betake	O
himself	O

to	O
the	O
practice	O
of	O
medicine	O
,	O
the	O
mathematics	O
might	O
have	O
had	O

another	O
Copernicus	B-PERSON
to	O
celebrate	O
.	O
Ramus	B-PERSON
,	O
then	O
,	O
was	O
for	O
astronomy	O

without	O
hypotheses	O
,	O
but	O
with	O
a	O
very	O
high	O
opinion	O
of	O
Copernicus	B-PERSON

and	O
of	O
his	O
system	O
as	O
against	O
previous	O
ones	O
;	O
so	O
far	O
his	O
meaning	O
is	O

not	O
very	O
clear	O
.	O
Mæstlinus	B-PERSON
took	O
him	O
literally	O
,	O
as	O
advocating	O
merely	O

7	O

*	O
It	O
must	O
,	O
however	O
,	O
he	O
observed	O
,	O
that	O
mind	O
and	O
matter	O
were	O
both	O
subjects	O
of	O
the	O

ancient	O
philosophy	O
,	O
physics	O
being	O
natural	O
philosophy	O
.	O
The	O
new	O
school	O
advocated	O

experimental	O
pliilosophy	O
,	O
professing	O
to	O
draw	O
all	O
their	O
conclusions	O
from	O
experiment	O
.	O

The	O
two	O
terms	O
were	O
antagonists	O
for	O
some	O
time	O
;	O
but	O
at	O
last	O
they	O
coalesced	O
and	O
for	O

more	O
than	O
a	O
century	O
writers	O
and	O
teachers	O
have	O
talked	O
of	O
natural	O
and	O
experimental	O

philosophy	O
,	O
a	O
combination	O
which	O
still	O
lingers	O
in	O
the	O
prospectuses	O
of	O
schools	O
and	O

lectures	O
.	O

+	O
It	O
is	O
impossible	O
to	O
keep	O
words	O
to	O
their	O
meanings	O
.	O
The	O
words	O
physician	O
and	O

naturalist	O
are	O
of	O
the	O
same	O
original	O
meaning	O
,	O
namely	O
,	O
investigators	O
of	O
the	O
external	O

world	O
;	O
but	O
the	O
first	O
now	O
means	O
a	O
person	O
who	O
looks	O
after	O
the	O
health	O
of	O
men	O
,	O
while	O
the	O

second	O
means	O
one	O
who	O
looks	O
after	O
the	O
classification	O
,	O
&	O
c	O
.	O
of	O
brutes	O
and	O
vegetabies	O
.	O

#	O
It	O
is	O
a	O
coincidence	O
of	O
date	O
worth	O
noting	O
,	O
with	O
reference	O
to	O
the	O
attack	O
on	O
the	O
old	O

system	O
,	O
that	O
the	O
astronomy	O
of	O
Copernicus	B-PERSON
and	O
the	O
logic	O
of	O
Ramus	B-PERSON
were	O
published	O
in	O

the	O
same	O
year	O
.	O

