he	O
principal	O
mountains	O
of	O
France	B-GPE
are	O
,	O
1	B-CARDINAL
.	O
The	O

Toeget	O
on	O
the	O
north	O
-	O
east	O
.	O
They	O
are	O
of	O
a	O
rounded	O
oat	O
-	O

Bne	O
,	O
with	O
gentle	O
slopes	O
,	O
and	O
afford	O
much	O
open	O
paa	O
-	O

turage	O
.	O
The	O
highest	O
summit	O
is	O
not	O
more	O
than	O
4500	B-QUANTITY

ftet	O
nigh	O
.	O
2	O
.	O
The	O
Jura	B-LOC
mountains	I-LOC
He	O
to	O
the	O
south	O
of	O

these	O
,	O
and	O
their	O
summiu	O
rise	O
to	O
the	O
height	O
of	O
0000	B-QUANTITY

feet	O
.	O
3	O
.	O
Many	O
Alpine	O
branches	O
intersect	O
Daaphlny	B-GPE

and	O
Provence	B-GPE
.	O
In	O
the	O
ceotre	O
of	O
the	O
kingdom	O
are	O
,	O
4	O
.	O

The	O
mountains	B-LOC
of	I-LOC
Auvergne	I-LOC
,	O
of	O
volcamo	O
origin	O
,	O
of	O

which	O
the	O
Puy	B-LOC
de	I-LOC
Dome	I-LOC
,	O
the	O
Moots	B-LOC
d'Or	I-LOC
,	O
and	O
the	O

Cental	O
,	O
are	O
the	O
principal	O
groups	O
.	O
5	O
.	O
The	O
Cerennee	O

Be	O
to	O
the	O
south	O
-	O
east	O
of	O
the	O
range	O
last	O
mentioned	O
.	O

Their	O
highest	O
summit	O
Is	O
Mont	B-LOC
Lozcre	I-LOC
(	O
about	O
C	O
510	B-QUANTITY

Ihet	O
)	O
.	O
0	O
.	O
The	O
Pyrenees	B-LOC
form	O
the	O
prlnnipai	O
part	O
of	O
the	O

boundary	O
between	O
France	B-GPE
and	O
Spain	B-GPE
.	O
These	O
moun	O
-	O

tains	O
divide	O
the	O
cou	O
.	O
utry	O
into	O
four	O
great	O
basins	O
,	O
the	O

form	O
and	O
exposure	O
of	O
which	O
necessarily	O
have	O
a	O
great	O

influence	O
on	O
their	O
climate	O
and	O
productions	O
.	O
The	O
nar	O
-	O

row	O
valley	O
of	O
the	O
Rhine	B-LOC
runs	O
from	O
nortli	O
to	O
<	O
ioutIi	O
,	O

while	O
the	O
open	O
basins	O
of	O
the	O
Seine	B-LOC
,	O
the	O
Loire	B-LOC
,	O
and	O
the	O

Garonne	B-LOC
,	O
stretch	O
iu	O
a	O
north	O
-	O
weslt	O
^	O
rn	O
direction	O
.	O
The	O

Adour	B-LOC
rises	O
in	O
the	O
Pyrenees	B-LOC
,	O
and	O
washes	O
the	O
walls	O
of	O

Bayonne	B-LOC
.	O
The	O
other	O
rivers	O
are	O
principally	O
tributa	O
-	O

jfes	O
.	O
The	O
Marne	B-LOC
and	O
the	O
Oise	B-LOC
fall	O
into	O
tne	O
Seine	B-LOC
;	O

the	O
Allier	O
,	O
the	O
Loire	B-LOC
,	O
the	O
Sarthe	B-LOC
,	O
and	O
the	O
Maycnne	B-LOC
,	O

into	O
the	O
Loire	B-LOC
;	O
the	O
Rhone	B-LOC
receives	O
the	O
Saoue	B-LOC
,	O
the	O

Isire	B-LOC
,	O
the	O
Durance	B-LOC
,	O
the	O
Ain	B-LOC
,	O
and	O
the	O
Sorgue	B-LOC
;	O
the	O

Tarn	B-LOC
and	O
the	O
Dordi	B-LOC
^	O
e	O
join	O
the	O
Garonne	B-LOC
.	O
The	O
nu	O
-	O

merous	O
branches	O
of	O
these	O
rivers	O
are	O
joined	O
by	O
canals	B-FAC
,	O

which	O
form	O
an	O
extensive	O
internal	O
water	O
communication	O
.	O

In	O
resprct	O
to	O
soil	O
,	O
the	O
richest	O
part	O
of	O
France	B-GPE
is	O
the	O

north	O
-	O
west	O
division	O
,	O
comprehending	O
the	O
provinces	O
of	O

Flanders	B-GPE
,	O
Artuis	B-GPE
,	O
Picardy	B-GPE
,	O
Normandy	B-GPE
,	O
and	O
the	O
Isle	B-GPE

of	I-GPE
France	I-GPE
,	O
where	O
there	O
is	O
a	O
deep	O
rich	O
loam	O
;	O
about	O

18	B-QUANTITY
,	I-QUANTITY
I	I-QUANTITY
70,51	I-QUANTITY
>	I-QUANTITY
0	I-QUANTITY
acres	O
in	O
extent	O
.	O
The	O
valley	O
of	O
the	O
Ga	B-LOC
-	I-LOC

ronne	I-LOC
ia	O
composed	O
of	O
a	O
friable	O
sandy	O
loam	O
,	O
with	O
a	O

calcareous	O
mixture	O
,	O
and	O
moisture	O
suthcient	O
for	O
every	O

purpose	O
.	O
This	O
district	O
contains	O
7	B-QUANTITY
)	I-QUANTITY
054,501	I-QUANTITY
acres	O
.	O
The	O

greet	O
valley	O
of	O
Languedoc	B-LOC
is	O
extremely	O
prolific	O
,	O
though	O

the	O
toil	O
is	O
not	O
so	O
fine	O
as	O
that	O
of	O
the	O
preceding	O
districts	O
.	O

The	O
Limarne	B-LOC
,	O
a	O
valley	O
of	O
Auvergne	B-GPE
,	O
Is	O
considered	O

to	O
have	O
one	O
of	O
the	O
finest	O
stjils	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
.	O
It	O
con	O
-	O

atsts	O
of	O
beds	O
of	O
earth	O
,	O
said	O
to	O
be	O
twenty	B-QUANTITY
feet	O
deep	O
,	O

formed	O
from	O
the	O
deojmposition	O
of	O
soft	O
basalt	O
.	O
The	O

calcareous	O
and	O
chalk	O
formations	O
are	O
extensive	O
.	O
Tlie	O

chalk	O
provinces	B-LOC
are	O
unfruitful	O
in	O
grain	O
,	O
but	O
the	O
genial	O

Influence	O
of	O
the	O
sun	O
allows	O
them	O
other	O
riches	O
.	O
The	O

calcarroiis	O
loam	O
on	O
the	O
borders	O
of	O
the	O
chalk	O
formation	O

is	O
more	O
productive	O
.	O
In	O
Bretagne	B-LOC
,	O
Anjou	B-LOC
,	O
and	O
Maine	B-LOC
,	O

are	O
immense	O
heaths	O
.	O
The	O
lanite	O
$	O
are	O
J	O
^	O
xtensive	O
tracts	O

of	O
sandy	O
deserts	O
,	O
producing	O
nothing	O
but	O
broom	O
,	O
heath	O
,	O

and	O
Junipers	O
.	O
The	O
most	O
extensive	O
are	O
the	O
landes	O
of	O

Bordeaux	B-LOC
,	O
twenty	O
leagues	O
in	O
length	O
by	O
twelve	O
In	O

breadth	O
.	O
In	O
the	O
remaining	O
provinces	B-LOC
,	O
gravel	O
,	O
or	O
a	O

gravelly	O
sand	O
,	O
is	O
the	O
predominating	O
soil	O
.	O
The	O
woods	O

and	O
forests	O
are	O
estimated	O
to	O
oover	O
a	O
space	O
of	O
10,795,000	O

acres	O
.	O
The	O
principal	O
are	O
tlioseof	O
Ardennes	B-GPE
,	O
Orleans	B-GPE
,	O

and	O
For	B-GPE
.	I-GPE
taincl'leau	I-GPE
.	O
The	O
northern	O
and	O
western	O
coasts	O

are	O
formed	O
iu	O
a	O
great	O
proportion	O
by	O
immense	O
downs	O

or	O
sandbanks	O
,	O
and	O
where	O
the	O
shores	O
are	O
formed	O
by	O

cliffs	O
,	O
they	O
are	O
seidnrii	O
bold	O
enough	O
to	O
be	O
approached	O

with	O
safety	O
.	O
The	O
harlwurs	O
are	O
therefore	O
tew	O
.	O
On	O

the	O
Mediterranean	B-LOC
,	O
the	O
cout	O
of	O
Languedoc	B-GPE
is	O
very	O

dangerous	O
,	O
but	O
Provence	B-GPE
abuands	O
in	O
good	O
barbourt	O
.	O

The	O
culture	O
,	O
throughout	O
the	O
northern	O
half	O
of	O
the	O

kingdom	O
,	O
consists	O
of	O
wheat	O
,	O
barley	B-PRODUCT
,	O
oats	B-PRODUCT
,	O
pulsct	O
*	O
nd	O
of	O

lata	O
,	O
much	O
more	O
than	O
formerlv	O
,	O
of	O
poutoes	B-PRODUCT
;	O
Iu	O
(	O
he	O

eoawem	O
half	O
,	O
com	O
(	O
particularly	O
malie	O
)	O
,	O
vintf	O
,	O
mtil	O
.	O

t	O
iMilMb	O
w	O
4	O
oUtm	O
.	O
Tba	O
eM	O
Um	O
parti	O
,	O
baloff	O

hmtlmf	O

>	O
puts	O
,	O
beiof	O
man	O

elevated	O
than	O
the	O
western	O
,	O
have	O
more	O
rigorous	O
winters	O

and	O
more	O
ardent	O
summers	O
.	O
Coal	B-PRODUCT
and	O
iron	B-PRODUCT
are	O
found	O

In	O
abundance	O
.	O
The	O
most	O
common	O
fuel	O
is	O
wood	O
.	O

The	O
superficial	O
extent	O
of	O
France	B-GPE
has	O
been	O
recently	O

estimated	O
by	O
Baron	B-PERSON
Dupin	I-PERSON
at	O
53,533,430	B-QUANTITY
hecures	O
,	O

or	O
139,094,000	B-NORP
English	O
acres	O
.	O
The	O
value	O
of	O
ca	O
-	O

piul	O
vested	O
in	O
agricultural	O
pursuits	O
Is	O
estimated	O
at	O

37.532,061,470	B-MONEY
francs	I-MONEY
:	O
the	O
gross	O
annual	O
produce	O
at	O

4	B-MONEY
,	I-MONEY
(	I-MONEY
>	I-MONEY
78,70	I-MONEY
R	I-MONEY
,	I-MONEY
805	I-MONEY
francs	I-MONEY
;	O
the	O
expenses	O
of	O
cultivation	O
at	O

3,334,005	B-MONEY
,	I-MONEY
.	I-MONEY
'	I-MONEY
>	I-MONEY
15	I-MONEY
;	O
leaving	O
a	O
profit	O
of	O
31	B-PERCENT
per	I-PERCENT
cent	I-PERCENT
,	O
on	O
the	O

capital	O
.	O
The	O
produce	O
of	O
wheat	B-PRODUCT
in	O
the	O
best	O
cultivated	O

distrlcu	O
,	O
and	O
on	O
the	O
best	O
soil	O
,	O
hardly	O
exceeds	O
eighteen	B-QUANTITY

bushels	I-QUANTITY
per	O
acre	O
:	O
an	O
English	O
farmer	O
exptcu	O
twenty	O
-	O

five	O
or	O
the	O
same	O
extent	O
.	O
In	O
1813	B-DATE
,	O
the	O
number	O
of	O

horstk	B-PRODUCT
A	O
France	O
was	O
9,170,000	B-CARDINAL
(	O
but	O
in	O
1810	B-DATE
,	O
the	O

horsMs	B-PRODUCT
and	O
mules	B-PRODUCT
together	O
amountad	O
only	O
to	O
1	O
}	O
657	O
,	O
C	O
7	O
1	O
;	O

at	O
present	O
the	O
number	O
is	O
estimated	O
at	O
2,500,000	B-CARDINAL
.	O
The	O

number	O
of	O
homed	O
cattle	O
Is	O
6,073,000	B-CARDINAL
1	I-CARDINAL
of	O
sheep	B-PRODUCT
,	O
about	O

45,0	O
e	O
^	O
000	O
.	O
The	O
total	O
number	O
of	O
all	O
kinds	O
of	O
poultry	B-PRODUCT

is	O
about	O
51,600,000	B-CARDINAL
.	O
The	O
French	B-NORP
are	O
tbe	O
best	O
wine	B-PRODUCT
-	O

makers	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
.	O
The	O
Champagne	O
,	O
Burgundy	O
,	O

Claret	O
,	O
Hermitage	O
,	O
are	O
drunk	O
all	O
over	O
the	O
world	O
.	O
For	O

a	O
long	O
time	O
,	O
the	O
choicest	O
growths	O
were	O
in	O
the	O
hands	O

of	O
the	O
church	B-NORP
;	O
and	O
in	O
the	O
frequent	O
changes	O
of	O
pre	O

party	O
which	O
have	O
taken	O
place	O
since	O
the	O
revolution	B-EVENT
,	O

many	O
vineyards	B-FAC
have	O
deteriorated	O
in	O
consequ	O
.	O
.	O
noe	O
of	O

bad	O
management	O
.	O
The	O
brandies	B-PRODUCT
of	O
France	B-GPE
are	O
the	O

best	O
in	O
the	O
world	O
.	O
The	O
value	O
of	O
the	O
whole	O
produce	O
of	O

V	B-PRODUCT
ine	I-PRODUCT
and	O
brandy	B-PRODUCT
Is	O
about	O
800,000,000	B-MONEY
of	I-MONEY
fianos	I-MONEY
.	O
The	O

culture	O
of	O
the	O
vine	O
Is	O
supposed	O
to	O
have	O
Increased	O
nearly	O

one	O
-	O
fourth	O
since	O
the	O
revolntion	B-EVENT
,	O
owing	O
principally	O
to	O

the	O
small	O
proprietors	O
,	O
each	O
of	O
whom	O
endeavours	O
to	O

supply	O
his	O
own	O
consumption	O
by	O
a	O
little	O
patch	O
of	O
vine	B-FAC
-	I-FAC

yard	I-FAC
.	O
M	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Dupin	I-PERSON
says	O
that	O
many	O
hectarca	O
of	O
f	O
ranch	O

territory	O
are	O
3	B-QUANTITY
*	I-QUANTITY
01	I-QUANTITY
uncultivated	O
,	O
merely	O
for	O
want	O
of	O
cat	B-PRODUCT
-	I-PRODUCT

tle	I-PRODUCT
to	O
stock	O
und	O
manure	O
them	O
;	O
that	O
twcthirda	O
of	O
the	O

inhabitaattf	O
are	O
without	O
aalmal	O
food	B-PRODUCT
;	O
that	O
more	O
than	O

oue	O
-	O
third	O
subsist	O
entirely	O
on	O
oats	B-PRODUCT
,	O
buckwheat	B-PRODUCT
,	O
rye	B-PRODUCT
,	O

chestnuts	B-PRODUCT
,	O
or	O
potatoe	B-PRODUCT
0	O
»	O
and	O
that	O
the	O
agricultural	O
popu	O
-	O

lation	O
is	O
loo	O
great	O
for	O
the	O
prosperity	O
of	O
France	B-GPE
.	O
Two	O
-	O

thirds	O
of	O
the	O
population	O
is	O
agrioulturaL	O

France	B-GPE
possesses	O
a	O
soil	O
and	O
climate	O
capable	O
of	O
fur	O
-	O

nlahlng	O
her	O
with	O
uil	O
the	O
raw	O
materials	O
of	O
mauufactare	O

except	O
cotton	B-PRODUCT
.	O
The	O
manufacture	O
of	O
fine	O
woollen	O

cloths	B-PRODUCT
at	O
Sedan	B-LOC
wu	O
introduced	O
under	O
the	O
auspices	O
of	O

Colbert	B-PERSON
.	O
The	O
machinery	O
used	O
was	O
very	O
defective	O
un	O
-	O

til	O
M	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Chaptal	I-PERSON
engaged	O
an	O
English	B-NORP
machinist	I-NORP
to	O
In	O
-	O

struct	O
the	O
French	B-NORP
aruxans	I-NORP
.	O
Steam	O
.	O
engines	O
are	O
rare	O
;	O

the	O
spinning	B-FAC
mills	I-FAC
being	O
worked	O
chiefly	O
by	O
water	O
or	O

by	O
horses	O
.	O
The	O
quantity	O
of	O
native	O
wool	B-PRODUCT
manufactured	O

in	O
1819	B-DATE
.	O
was	O
38,000,000	B-QUANTITY
kilogrammes	I-QUANTITY
(	O
of	O
about	O
3	B-QUANTITY
|	I-QUANTITY
lbs	I-QUANTITY
.	O

each	O
)	O
,	O
and	O
,	O
in	O
1836	B-DATE
,	O
4	B-QUANTITY
^	I-QUANTITY
,	I-QUANTITY
000,000	I-QUANTITY
,	O
with	O
H	O
,	O
000,000	B-QUANTITY
of	O
im	O
-	O

ported	O
wool	B-PRODUCT
:	O
the	O
value	O
of	O
the	O
roanuiactured	O
articles	O

was	O
305,000,000	B-MONEY
francs	I-MONEY
;	O
of	O
the	O
raw	B-PRODUCT
wool	I-PRODUCT
,	O
105,000,000	B-QUANTITY
:	O

the	O
quantity	O
exported	O
was	O
about	O
one	O
-	O
thirteenth	O
of	O
the	O

whole	O
quantity	O
manufactured	O
.	O
By	O
the	O
exertions	O
of	O

Henry	B-PERSON
IV	I-PERSON
.	O
,	O
the	O
mulberry	B-PRODUCT
.	I-PRODUCT
tree	I-PRODUCT
was	O
cultivated	O
in	O
all	O
the	O

southern	B-LOC
provinces	I-LOC
.	O
At	O
Tours	B-GPE
,	O
silk	B-PRODUCT
stuffs	O
for	O
furniture	B-PRODUCT

are	O
chiefly	O
manufactured	O
;	O
at	O
Ganges	B-GPE
,	O
and	O
other	O
places	O

in	O
the	O
Cevennes	B-LOC
,	O
silk	B-PRODUCT
stockings	I-PRODUCT
.	O
Lyons	B-GPE
is	O
the	O
princi	O
-	O

pal	O
place	O
for	O
silk	B-PRODUCT
manufactures	O
of	O
all	O
kinds	O
.	O
Paris	B-GPE

ranks	O
next	O
after	O
Lyons	B-GPE
.	O
In	O
181	B-DATE
'	O
.	O
!	O
,	O
the	O
value	O
of	O
the	O

raw	O
material	O
amounted	O
to	O
45,500	B-MONEY
,	I-MONEY
(	I-MONEY
HIO	I-MONEY
francs	I-MONEY
,	O
of	O
which	O

33,000,000	B-QUANTITY
were	O
the	O
price	O
of	O
imported	O
silk	B-PRODUCT
.	O
The	O
va	O
-	O

lue	O
of	O
manufactured	B-PRODUCT
goods	I-PRODUCT
,	O
at	O
the	O
same	O
period	O
,	O
was	O

107,500,000	O
francs	O
,	O
m'	O
which	O
less	O
than	O
one	O
-	O
third	O
was	O

exported	O
.	O
Forty	O
years	O
ago	O
,	O
the	O
spinning	O
of	O
cotton	B-PRODUCT
by	O

machinery	O
waa	O
hardly	O
practised	O
in	O
France	B-GPE
.	O
Cotton	B-PRODUCT

mills	O
have	O
l	O
>	O
een	O
established	O
within	O
that	O
period	O
,	O
and	O

the	O
manufactures	O
of	O
Alsace	B-GPE
are	O
now	O
superior	O
to	O
those	O

of	O
England	B-GPE
in	O
the	O
brilliaucy	O
of	O
their	O
colours	O
.	O
In	O
11113	B-DATE
,	O

l	O
0	O
,	O
:	O
Ui	O
3,000	B-QUANTITY
kilogrammes	I-QUANTITY
of	O
oitton	B-PRODUCT
were	O
spun	O
by	O
ma	O
-	O

chinery	O
,	O
and	O
,	O
iit	O
1	O
H	O
2	O
A	O
,	O
'	O
JM	O
,	O
(	O
M	O
)	O
0,000	O
of	O
greater	O
fineness	O
.	O

The	O
cambrics	B-PRODUCT
,	O
gaiue	B-PRODUCT
,	O
aiul	B-PRODUCT
lawn	I-PRODUCT
of	O
St	B-GPE
Quentin	I-GPE
,	O
Valen	B-GPE
-	I-GPE

ciennes	I-GPE
,	O
and	O
Cambray	B-GPE
,	O
are	O
among	O
the	O
most	O
valuable	O

products	O
of	O
French	O
Industry	O
.	O
Lace	B-PRODUCT
is	O
made	O
in	O
great	O

quantities	O
.	O

The	O
whole	O
produce	O
of	O
the	O
linen	B-PRODUCT
and	O
hemp	B-PRODUCT
manu	O
-	O

factures	O
is	O
estimated	O
at	O
300,00	B-MONEY
(	I-MONEY
»	I-MONEY
,	I-MONEY
000	I-MONEY
francs	I-MONEY
.	O
L	O
.	O
1814	B-DATE
,	O

100,000,000	B-QUANTITY
kilogrammes	I-QUANTITY
of	O
cast	O
-	O
iron	O
were	O
produced	O
;	O

in	O
1825	B-DATE
,	O
180,000,000	B-QUANTITY
.	O
<	O
IildinK	O
tnd	O
watch	O
-	O
making	O
are	O

carried	O
on	O
,	O
chiefly	O
in	O
Paris	B-GPE
,	O
t	O
>	O
>	O
the	O
annual	O
value	O
of	O

about	O
38,000,000	B-MONEY
francs	I-MONEY
each	O
.	O
Printing	O
also	O
employs	O

a	O
great	O
number	O
of	O
persons	O
at	O
Paris	B-GPE
.	O
In	O
IRU	O
,	O
the	O

number	O
of	O
printed	O
sheets	O
was	O
45,075,030	B-CARDINAL
;	O
in	O
1820	B-DATE
,	O

80,031,303	B-CARDINAL
;	O
and	O
in	O
1830	B-DATE
,	O
144,58	O
I	O
,	O
(	O
MI	O
4	O
.	O
NotwJth	O
.	O

standing	O
the	O
low	O
price	O
of	O
labour	O
iu	O
France	B-GPE
,	O
the	O
in	O
-	O

dustry	O
of	O
that	O
c	O
<	O
iuntry	O
cannot	O
enter	O
into	O
competition	O

withUiatof	O
England	B-GPE
.	O
One	O
of	O
the	O
circumstances	O
which	O

depress	O
it	O
is	O
the	O
want	O
of	O
internal	O
communication	O
by	O

roads	B-FAC
and	O
canals	B-FAC
.	O
The	O
practicable	O
roads	B-FAC
of	O
France	O

are	O
not	O
more	O
than	O
one	O
-	O
third	O
of	O
the	O
extent	O
of	O
those	O
of	O

England	B-GPE
.	O
The	O
cross	B-FAC
-	I-FAC
roeds	I-FAC
are	O
few	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
great	O

roads	B-FAC
are	O
seldom	O
kept	O
in	O
good	O
order	O
.	O
The	O
length	O
of	O

the	O
canals	B-FAC
in	O
France	B-GPE
is	O
not	O
more	O
than	O
one	O
-	O
eleventh	O
of	O

those	O
of	O
England	B-GPE
.	O
Another	O
point	O
in	O
which	O
France	B-GPE
is	O

inferior	O
is	O
in	O
the	O
use	O
of	O
steam	B-FAC
.	I-FAC
engines	I-FAC
,	O
attributable	O
In	O

part	O
to	O
the	O
deficiency	O
of	O
coal	O
,	O
or	O
the	O
dlHiculty	O
of	O
trans	O
-	O

porting	O
it	O
.	O
The	O
total	O
force	O
of	O
steam	B-FAC
-	I-FAC
engines	I-FAC
iu	O
France	B-GPE
,	O

according	O
to	O
Dupin	B-PERSON
,	O
is	O
ecpial	O
to	O
Jiat	O
ol	O
480	O
,	O
(	O
f	O
(	O
K	O
>	O
men	O
;	O

that	O
of	O
England	B-GPE
is	O
equal	O
to	O
a	O
powei	O
of	O
li	O
,	O
44	O
K	O
)	O
,	O
OlN	O
)	O
men	O
.	O

All	O
the	O
power	O
derived	O
from	O
machinery	O
of	O
every	O
sort	O
,	O

or	O
from	O
constructive	O
ingenuity	O
,	O
and	O
applied	O
to	O
pur	O
-	O

poses	O
of	O
industry	O
in	O
France	B-GPE
,	O
is	O
tinly	O
one	O
-	O
fourth	O
of	O
the	O

similar	O
power	O
employed	O
in	O
England	B-GPE
.	O

The	O
commerce	O
ot	O
France	O
has	O
l	O
>	O
ecn	O
vary	O
ranch	O
di	O
-	O

minished	O
by	O
the	O
loss	O
of	O
her	O
colonies	B-LOC
.	O
The	O
value	O
of	O

the	O
cokinial	O
importa	O
,	O
in	O
1788	B-DATE
,	O
was	O
337,0	B-MONEY
tW	I-MONEY
,	I-MONEY
'	I-MONEY
i	I-MONEY
00	I-MONEY
francs	I-MONEY
;	O

iti	O
1834	B-DATE
,	O
it	O
waa	O
only	O
50,000,000	B-MONEY
.	O
The	O
exporu	O
for	O

17	O
«	O
lMMWrtiil	O
«	O
U	O
9	O
/	O
>	O
00	O
}	O
009	O
(	O
in	O
iaM	O
,	O
to	O
44,00	O
(	O
^	O
0	O
«	O
0	O
.	O

The	O
total	O
value	O
of	O
exports	O
from	O
France	B-GPE
,	O
in	O
1834	B-DATE
,	O
was	O

440,543,000	B-MONEY
francs	I-MONEY
t	O
of	O
which	O
103,050,000	B-MONEY
were	O
pro	O
.	O

ductions	O
of	O
the	O
country	O
,	O
and	O
277,486,000	B-MONEY
manufactured	B-PRODUCT

articles	O
.	O
The	O
amount	O
exported	O
to	O
the	O
United	B-GPE
States	I-GPE

waa	O
55,000,000	B-MONEY
,	O
being	O
more	O
than	O
that	O
to	O
any	O
other	O

country	O
.	O
The	O
imports	O
for	O
the	O
same	O
year	O
were	O
of	O
the	O

value	O
of	O
454,801,000	B-MONEY
francs	I-MONEY
;	O
of	O
which	O
373,873,000	B-MONEY

franoswerersw	O
materials	B-PRODUCT
for	I-PRODUCT
manufacture	I-PRODUCT
,	O
121	O
.	O
9	O
r	O
)	O
7,000	O

natural	B-PRODUCT
productions	I-PRODUCT
for	I-PRODUCT
consumption	I-PRODUCT
,	O
and	O
00	O
,	O
o	O
:	O
tO	O
,	O
000	O

manufactured	B-PRODUCT
articles	I-PRODUCT
.	O
In	O
1824	B-DATE
,	O
the	O
number	O
of	O
sailora	O

in	O
French	O
ships	B-FAC
was	O
328,480	B-CARDINAL
;	O
of	O
whom	O
28,040	B-CARDINAL
were	O

engaged	O
in	O
foreign	O
commerce	O
,	O
47,383	B-CARDINAL
in	O
the	O
fisheries	B-FAC
,	O

and	O
the	O
remainder	O
in	O
the	O
coasting	O
trade	O
.	O
The	O
navy	B-NORP
,	O

according	O
to	O
the	O
budget	O
of	O
1838	B-DATE
,	O
consisted	O
of	O
38	B-CARDINAL
ships	B-FAC

of	O
the	O
iioe	O
,	O
35	B-CARDINAL
frigates	B-FAC
,	O
8	B-CARDINAL
steam	B-FAC
.	O
boaU	O
,	O
and	O
186	B-CARDINAL
other	O

veasels	B-FAC
,	O
and	O
14,003	B-CARDINAL
officera	B-NORP
and	O
sailors	B-NORP
.	O
The	O
army	B-NORP
la	O

1828 am	B-DATE
ounted	O
to	O
233,770	B-CARDINAL
men	O
,	O
and	O
was	O
recruited	O
by	O

voluntary	O
enlistment	O
and	O
annual	O
levies	O
,	O
every	O
French	B-NORP
-	I-NORP

man	I-NORP
of	O
twenty	O
years	O
of	O
age	O
being	O
bound	O
to	O
serve	O
for	O

a	O
term	O
of	O
eight	O
years	O
.	O
The	O
reoelpu	O
of	O
1828	B-DATE
were	O

l	B-MONEY
,	I-MONEY
037	I-MONEY
,	I-MONEY
iO	I-MONEY
4,4	I-MONEY
»	I-MONEY
l	I-MONEY
francs	I-MONEY
;	O
the	O
expenditure	O
,	O
1,035,415,552	B-MONEY

franos	I-MONEY
.	O

As	O
we	O
have	O
glren	O
the	O
history	O
of	O
the	O
French	B-EVENT
Revo	I-EVENT
-	I-EVENT

lution	I-EVENT
of	O
1780	B-DATE
in	O
another	O
portion	O
of	O
the	O
present	O
work	O

(	O
No	O
.	O
9	O
)	O
,	O
nothing	O
need	O
here	O
be	O
said	O
of	O
that	O
event	O
.	O
It	O

is	O
suflident	O
to	O
state	O
that	O
the	O
military	B-NORP
character	O
which	O

was	O
engrafted	O
upon	O
the	O
nation	B-NORP
by	O
subsequent	O
eventa	O

still	O
predominates	O
,	O
and	O
may	O
be	O
described	O
as	O
one	O
of	O
the	O

main	O
causes	O
fur	O
the	O
deficiency	O
of	O
France	O
in	O
manufac	B-FAC
-	I-FAC

tures	I-FAC
,	O
comn	O
.	O
eroe	O
,	O
wealth	O
,	O
and	O
many	O
comforts	O
of	O
social	O

life	O
.	O
The	O
character	O
of	O
the	O
Frei	O
«	O
oh	O
,	O
however	O
.	O
Is	O
fwt	O

undergoing	O
an	O
improvement	O
under	O
the	O
constitution	B-LAW

which	O
the	O
country	O
has	O
enjoyv	O
.	O
d	O
since	O
1830	B-DATE
,	O
when	O

Louis	B-PERSON
Philip	I-PERSON
waa	O
placed	O
on	O
the	O
throne	B-NORP
,	O
by	O
the	O
events	O

of	O
what	O
are	O
termed	O
the	O
"	O
three	B-EVENT
days	I-EVENT
,	O
*	O
*	O
or	O
the	O
revolu	B-EVENT
-	I-EVENT

tion	I-EVENT
which	O
deposed	O
the	O
elder	O
line	O
of	O
the	O
Bourbons	B-NORP
.	O

The	O
present	O
reigning	O
family	O
,	O
or	O
house	B-NORP
of	I-NORP
Orleans	I-NORP
,	O
le	O

a	O
collateral	O
line	O
of	O
^	O
e	O
former	O
branch	O
,	O
being	O
derived	O

from	O
the	O
onlv	O
brother	O
of	O
Louis	B-PERSON
XIV	I-PERSON
.	O
,	O
Philip	B-PERSON
Duke	I-PERSON
of	I-PERSON

Orleans	I-PERSON
.	O
The	O
following	O
are	O
the	O
eras	O
of	O
the	O
reigning	O

princes	O
of	O
France	B-GPE
:	O
—	O
1	O
.	O
Capet	B-PERSON
Dyruuty	I-PERSON
:	O
Hugh	B-PERSON
Capet	I-PERSON

(	O
987	B-DATE
)	O
,	O
died	O
900	B-DATE
;	O
Robert	B-PERSON
,	O
dieh	O
'	O
031	B-DATE
;	O
Henry	B-PERSON
L	I-PERSON
,	O
died	O

1080	B-DATE
;	O
Philip	B-PERSON
L	I-PERSON
,	O
died	O
1108	B-DATE
;	O
L	B-PERSON
uis	I-PERSON
IV	I-PERSON
.	O
,	O
died	O
113	B-DATE
?	I-DATE
t	O

liouis	B-PERSON
Vn	I-PERSON
.	O
,	O
died	O
1180	O
;	O
Philip	B-PERSON
il	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
(	O
Augustus	B-PERSON
)	O
,	O
died	O

1233	B-DATE
;	O
Louis	B-PERSON
VIII	I-PERSON
.	O
,	O
died	O
1336	B-DATE
;	O
Louis	B-PERSON
IX	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
(	I-PERSON
the	I-PERSON
Saint	I-PERSON
)	I-PERSON
,	O

died	O
1370	B-DATE
;	O
Philip	B-PERSON
III	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
(	I-PERSON
the	I-PERSON
Bold	I-PERSON
)	I-PERSON
,	O
died	O
1285	B-DATE
;	O
Philip	B-PERSON

IV	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
(	I-PERSON
the	I-PERSON
Fair	I-PERSON
)	I-PERSON
,	O
died	O
1314	B-DATE
;	O
Louts	B-PERSON
X	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
(	I-PERSON
Hutin	I-PERSON
)	I-PERSON
,	O
died	O

1310	B-DATE
;	O
Philip	B-PERSON
V	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
(	I-PERSON
the	I-PERSON
liong	I-PERSON
)	I-PERSON
,	O
died	O
1331	B-DATE
;	O
Charles	B-PERSON
IV	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON

(	I-PERSON
the	I-PERSON
Fair	I-PERSON
)	I-PERSON
,	O
died	O
133	B-DATE
a	I-DATE
—	I-DATE
3	I-DATE
.	O
Branch	B-PERSON
0	I-PERSON
/	I-PERSON
Vahitt	I-PERSON
Philip	I-PERSON

VL	I-PERSON
,	O
died	O
1350	B-DATE
;	O
John	B-PERSON
(	O
the	O
(	O
iw	O
>	O
d	O
\	O
died	O
VMA	O
;	O
ChaHee	B-PERSON

V	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
(	I-PERSON
the	I-PERSON
Wise	I-PERSON
)	I-PERSON
,	O
died	O
1380	B-DATE
;	O
Charles	B-PERSON
VI	I-PERSON
.	O
,	O
died	O
1433	B-DATE
;	O

Charles	B-PERSON
VIL	I-PERSON
,	O
died	O
1401	B-DATE
;	O
Louis	B-PERSON
XI	I-PERSON
.	O
,	O
died	O
1463	B-DATE
;	O

Charles	B-PERSON
VIIL	I-PERSON
,	O
died	O
1407	B-DATE
3	O
.	O
Branch	O
t	O
^	O
f	O
Orlearur	O

Louis	B-PERSON
XIL	I-PERSON
,	O
died	O
1515	B-DATE
;	O
Francis	B-PERSON
I	I-PERSON
.	O
,	O
died	O
1547	B-DATE
;	O
Henry	B-PERSON

IL	I-PERSON
,	O
died	O
1550	B-DATE
;	O
Francis	O
IL	O
,	O
died	O
1560	B-DATE
;	O
Charles	B-PERSON
IX	I-PERSON
.	O
,	O

died	O
1574	B-DATE
;	O
Henry	B-PERSON
IIL	I-PERSON
,	O
died	O
1580	B-DATE
.	O
—	O
4	O
.	O
Branch	O
qf	O

Bourhm	O
:	O
Henry	B-PERSON
IV	I-PERSON
.	O
,	O
died	O
1610	B-DATE
;	O
Louis	B-PERSON
XIIL	I-PERSON
,	O
died	O

1643	B-DATE
;	O
LoiHs	B-PERSON
XIV	I-PERSON
.	O
,	O
died	O
1715	B-DATE
;	O
Louis	B-PERSON
XV	I-PERSON
.	O
,	O
died	O
1774	O
;	O

Louis	B-PERSON
XVI	I-PERSON
.	O
,	O
died	O
1793	B-DATE
;	O
Louis	B-PERSON
XVU	I-PERSON
.	O
,	O
died	O
17	O
!	O
»	O
6	O
.	O

[	O
French	B-NORP
republic	I-NORP
,	O
from	O
1703	B-DATE
to	O
1804	B-DATE
;	O
Napoleon	B-PERSON
(	O
Bo	O
-	O

naparte	O
^	O
,	O
Emperor	B-NORP
of	I-NORP
the	I-NORP
French	I-NORP
,	O
from	O
1804	B-DATE
to	O
1814	B-DATE
.	O
]	O

^	O
Uouroons	O
restored	O
by	O
foreign	O
arms	O
:	O
Louis	B-PERSON
XVIIL	I-PERSON
,	O

from	O
1814	B-DATE
,	O
died	O
1024	B-DATE
;	O
Charles	B-PERSON
,	O
to	O
1830	B-DATE
,	O
when	O
he	O
was	O

dethroned	O
.	O
-	O
-	O
5	O
.	O
\	O
ew	O
House	B-NORP
of	I-NORP
Orleans	I-NORP
;	O
Louis	B-PERSON
Philip	I-PERSON

I	O
.	O
,	O
with	O
the	O
title	O
of	O
King	B-NORP
of	I-NORP
the	I-NORP
French	I-NORP
{	O
roi	O
-	O
Htoyen	O
)	O
,	O

Of	O
the	O
dethroned	O
Bourbon	B-NORP
family	I-NORP
,	O
there	O
are	O
living	O

the	O
ex	O
-	O
king	O
,	O
Charles	B-PERSON
X	I-PERSON
.	O
;	O
his	O
son	O
,	O
Louis	B-PERSON
Antoine	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Duke	I-PERSON

of	I-PERSON
Angouldme	I-PERSON
(	I-PERSON
late	I-PERSON
dauphin	I-PERSON
)	I-PERSON
,	O
bom	O
August	B-DATE
6	I-DATE
,	I-DATE
1775	I-DATE
;	O

married	O
his	O
cousin	O
,	O
Marie	B-PERSON
Therese	I-PERSON
,	O
daughter	O
of	O
Louie	B-PERSON

XVI	I-PERSON
.	O
The	O
second	O
son	O
of	O
Charles	B-PERSON
X	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Duke	I-PERSON
of	I-PERSON
Berry	I-PERSON
,	O

born	O
Jan	B-DATE
.	I-DATE
24	I-DATE
,	I-DATE
1778	I-DATE
;	O
married	O
to	O
Caroline	B-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Princess	I-PERSON
of	I-PERSON

Naples	I-PERSON
(	O
born	O
Nov	B-DATE
.	I-DATE
5	I-DATE
,	I-DATE
1708	I-DATE
)	O
;	O
was	O
assassinated	O
by	O

Louvain	B-PERSON
.	O
Feb	B-DATE
,	I-DATE
14	I-DATE
,	I-DATE
1820	I-DATE
.	O
His	O
children	O
are	O
Maria	B-PERSON

Louise	I-PERSON
(	I-PERSON
Mile	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
d	I-PERSON
*	I-PERSON
Artois	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Imrn	O
Sept	B-DATE
.	I-DATE
21	I-DATE
,	I-DATE
1819	I-DATE
)	O
,	O
and	O

Henry	B-PERSON
(	I-PERSON
Charles	I-PERSON
Ferdinrnd	I-PERSON
Marie	I-PERSON
DieudonnL'	I-PERSON
)	I-PERSON
,	O
Duke	B-PERSON

(	O
>	O
f	O
Bordeaux	O
,	O
born	O
.	O
Kept	O
.	O
20	O
,	O
1820	B-DATE
,	O
after	O
the	O
death	O
of	O

his	O
father	O
,	O
late	O
heir	O
.	O
presumptive	O
.	O
Charles	B-PERSON
and	O
the	O

dauphin	O
abdicatetl	O
In	O
his	O
favour	O
,	O
calling	O
him	O
Kiag	B-PERSON

Henry	I-PERSON
V	I-PERSON
.	O
I	B-PERSON
<	I-PERSON
ouis	I-PERSON
Philip	I-PERSON
has	O
a	O
family	O
of	O
five	O
sons	O
and	O

three	O
daughters	O
;	O
the	O
eldest	O
son	O
,	O
Ferdinand	B-PERSON
PhtUp	I-PERSON

Louis	B-PERSON
Charles	I-PERSON
Henry	I-PERSON
,	O
now	O
Duke	B-PERSON
of	I-PERSON
Orleans	I-PERSON
,	O
waa	O

born	O
in	O
1810	B-DATE
.	O

