#	O
#	O
p	O
.	O
(	O
#	O
5	O
)	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O

IReport	O

W	O
E	O
have	O
much	O
to	O
rejoice	O
us	O
this	O
year	O
in	O
the	O
various	O
departments	O
of	O

our	O
Society	B-ORG
’	O
s	O
work	O
.	O

Our	O
Publications	B-PRODUCT
.	O

The	O
Grace	O
Examinations	O
to	O
commemorate	O
the	O
Empress	B-PERSON
Dowager	I-PERSON

reaching	O
the	O
age	O
of	O
60	O
were	O
held	O
simultaneously	O
in	O
September	B-DATE
.	O
It	O
is	O
a	O

high	O
gratification	O
to	O
us	O
to	O
announce	O
that	O
through	O
special	O
funds	O
,	O
appealed	O

for	O
to	O
meet	O
this	O
special	O
occasion	O
,	O
we	O
succeeded	O
in	O
sending	O
6,000	B-CARDINAL
of	O
our	O

publications	B-PRODUCT
to	O
each	O
of	O
the	O
ten	B-CARDINAL
maritime	O
provinces	B-LOC
,	O
making	O
60,000	B-CARDINAL
in	O

all	O
.	O
720,000	B-CARDINAL
pages	B-PRODUCT
were	O
thus	O
distributed	O
gratis	B-MONEY
,	O
a	O
number	O
far	O
in	O
advance	O

of	O
anything	O
our	O
Society	B-ORG
has	O
ever	O
done	O
before	O
.	O

Another	O
ambition	O
of	O
ours	O
was	O
the	O
establishment	O
of	O
Branch	B-ORG
Depdts	I-ORG

in	O
the	O
provinces	B-LOC
for	O
the	O
sale	O
of	O
our	O
Publications	B-PRODUCT
.	O
We	O
have	O
now	O
Depots	O

in	O
Peking	B-GPE
,	O
in	O
Moukden	B-GPE
,	O
in	O
Tientsin	B-GPE
,	O
Shensi	B-GPE
,	O
in	O
Nanking	B-GPE
and	O
in	O
Chefoo	B-GPE
,	O

with	O
the	O
small	O
supply	O
of	O
$	B-MONEY
100	I-MONEY
worth	O
of	O
literature	O
in	O
each	O
to	O
start	O
with	O
.	O

The	O
work	O
which	O
will	O
make	O
this	O
year	O
most	O
memorable	O
however	O
,	O
is	O

the	O
republication	O
of	O
Dr	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Faber	I-PERSON
’	O
s	O
great	O
work	O
on	O
Civilization	O
,	O
a	O
book	B-PRODUCT
in	O

5	B-CARDINAL
Chinese	B-LANGUAGE
Volumes	O
,	O
and	O
treating	O
of	O
all	O
the	O
leading	O
forces	O
of	O
Western	B-LOC

Civilization	I-LOC
.	O
Thanks	O
to	O
the	O
generosity	O
of	O
the	O
Rev	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
P	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Kranz	I-PERSON
we	O
have	O

published	O
an	O
edition	B-PRODUCT
of	O
two	B-CARDINAL
thousand	I-CARDINAL
copies	B-PRODUCT
,	O
so	O
that	O
we	O
shall	O
be	O
able	O

to	O
present	O
all	O
the	O
great	O
Mandarins	B-NORP
of	O
the	O
Empire	B-GPE
with	O
a	O
copy	O
each	O
.	O

We	O
have	O
also	O
republished	O
the	O
work	O
which	O
the	O
late	O
Dr	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Williamson	I-PERSON

was	O
publishing	O
when	O
he	O
died	O
,	O
viz	O
:	O
What	O
a	O
Nation	O
Needs	O
.	O
This	O
is	O
at	O
the	O

request	O
of	O
the	O
members	O
of	O
the	B-NORP
English	I-NORP
Baptist	I-NORP
Mission	I-NORP
,	O
who	O
wish	O
to	O

have	O
it	O
for	O
circulation	O
and	O
who	O
meet	O
the	O
expense	O
of	O
publication	O
.	O
But	O

the	O
stereotyping	O
of	O
several	O
of	O
these	O
works	B-PRODUCT
for	O
future	O
use	O
has	O
involved	O

considerable	O
expense	O
.	O

The	O
book	B-PRODUCT
on	O
the	O
Benefits	O
of	O
Christianity	O
has	O
been	O
sold	O
out	O
at	O
its	O
full	O

cost	O
price	O
,	O
and	O
a	O
new	O
edition	O
has	O
therefore	O
been	O
ordered	O
.	O

#	O
#	O
p	O
.	O
(	O
#	O
6	O
)	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O

8	O

We	O
have	O
published	O
Mr	O
.	O
George	B-PERSON
Jamieson	I-PERSON
’	O
s	O
Article	O
on	O
English	O
Law	O

in	O
China	B-GPE
.	O
The	O
outline	O
of	O
the	O
Rise	O
and	O
Progress	O
of	O
the	O
Christian	O
En	O
¬	O

deavour	O
movement	O
,	O
now	O
numbering	O
millions	B-CARDINAL
of	O
followers	O
,	O
published	O

in	O
the	O
Missionary	O
Review	O
,	O
was	O
republished	O
by	O
the	O
United	B-ORG
Society	I-ORG
of	I-ORG

Christian	I-ORG
Endeavour	I-ORG
for	I-ORG
China	I-ORG
,	O
and	O
stereotyped	O
by	O
us	O
.	O
Dr	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Faber	I-PERSON
’	O
s	O

Chinese	B-LANGUAGE
Theories	O
of	O
Human	O
Nature	O
is	O
in	O
press	O
.	O
Miss	B-PERSON
Harvie	I-PERSON
,	O
Secretary	O
of	O

the	O
Ladies	B-PERSON
’	I-PERSON
Society	I-PERSON
in	O
Glasgow	B-GPE
,	O
has	O
sent	O
us	O
a	O
box	O
of	O
the	O
beautiful	O

chrome	O
of	O
The	O
Better	O
Land	O
,	O
which	O
will	O
form	O
the	O
finest	O
illustration	O
ever	O

put	O
out	O
for	O
Chinese	O
homes	O
.	O
The	O
Secretaries	B-ORG
of	O
the	O
Christian	B-ORG
Literature	I-ORG

Society	I-ORG
in	O
Glasgow	B-GPE
have	O
also	O
sent	O
us	O
a	O
fine	O
collection	O
of	O
electros	O
for	O

illustrating	O
our	O
magazines	B-PRODUCT
and	O
books	B-PRODUCT
.	O
The	O
Progress	O
of	O
Surrounding	O

Nations	O
;	O
Agricultural	O
Chemistry	O
;	O
the	O
Value	O
of	O
the	O
Doctrine	O
of	O
Immortality	O
;	O

Mrs	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Foster	I-PERSON
on	O
Persecutions	O
in	O
Madagascar	B-GPE
and	O
Christian	O
Missions	O
in	O
the	O

South	B-LOC
Sea	I-LOC
,	O
and	O
Daily	O
Readings	O
also	O
by	O
her	O
,	O
have	O
all	O
appeared	O
serially	O

in	O
our	O
periodicals	B-PRODUCT
and	O
will	O
be	O
published	O
separately	O
.	O
A	O
Universal	O

History	O
is	O
being	O
translated	O
for	O
our	O
Society	B-ORG
.	O
Mackenzie	B-PERSON
’	O
s	O
Nineteenth	B-DATE

Century	I-DATE
is	O
also	O
being	O
translated	O
;	O
it	O
will	O
give	O
much	O
needed	O
and	O
most	O

valuable	O
information	O
regarding	O
the	O
latest	O
progress	O
of	O
the	O
nations	O
of	O
the	O

West	B-LOC
.	O

Our	O
Magazines	O
.	O

Of	O
the	O
value	O
of	O
the	O
Review	O
of	O
the	O
limes	O
we	O
have	O
had	O
assurances	O
from	O

Formosa	B-GPE
and	O
from	O
Shantung	B-GPE
in	O
increased	O
orders	O
for	O
it	O
,	O
and	O
also	O
in	O
reprints	O

of	O
some	O
of	O
our	O
Articles	B-PRODUCT
in	O
the	O
Chinese	B-LANGUAGE
Daily	O
Papers	O
.	O
Of	O
the	O
value	O
of	O

the	O
Missionary	O
Review	O
we	O
also	O
have	O
assurance	O
in	O
the	O
fact	O
that	O
we	O
had	O
to	O

increase	O
the	O
number	O
printed	O
,	O
and	O
also	O
in	O
the	O
frequent	O
republication	O
of	O

some	O
of	O
our	O
Articles	B-PRODUCT
in	O
other	O
Chinese	B-LANGUAGE
religious	O
papers	B-PRODUCT
.	O
In	O
it	O
we	O
have	O

kept	O
in	O
mind	O
the	O
wishes	O
of	O
the	O
Ladies	B-ORG
’	I-ORG
Branch	I-ORG
in	O
Glasgow	B-GPE
,	O
who	O
help	O

us	O
so	O
nobly	O
,	O
and	O
have	O
had	O
much	O
of	O
its	O
contents	O
suited	O
to	O
give	O
informa	B-PRODUCT
¬	I-PRODUCT

tion	I-PRODUCT
in	O
the	O
department	O
they	O
have	O
chosen	O
.	O
But	O
as	O
it	O
does	O
not	O
cover	O
all	O

the	O
objects	O
they	O
have	O
in	O
view	O
,	O
we	O
must	O
suspend	O
its	O
publication	O
for	O
a	O
time	O

in	O
order	O
to	O
publish	O
the	O
Women	O
and	O
Children	O
’	O
s	O
Series	O
)	O
unless	O
we	O
obtain	O

more	O
funds	O
immediately	O
.	O

Dr	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Allen	I-PERSON
’	O
s	O
Return	O
.	O

Happily	O
Dr	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Allen	I-PERSON
,	O
who	O
has	O
rendered	O
such	O
valuable	O
service	O
in	O

editing	O
our	O
Magazines	B-PRODUCT
,	O
has	O
now	O
returned	O
from	O
his	O
visit	O
to	O
the	O
United	B-GPE

States	I-GPE
,	O
and	O
will	O
resume	O
the	O
editorial	O
work	O
in	O
connection	O
with	O
which	O
he	O

is	O
so	O
well	O
and	O
widely	O
known	O
.	O

#	O
#	O
p	O
.	O
(	O
#	O
7	O
)	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O

9	O

China	B-GPE
’	O
s	O
Enormous	O
Need	O
of	O
Enlightenment	O
.	O

China	B-GPE
’	O
s	O
losses	O
and	O
suffering	O
for	O
want	O
of	O
enlightenment	O
are	O
simply	O

appalling	O
.	O

For	O
want	O
of	O
political	O
insight	O
she	O
had	O
lost	O
within	O
the	O
last	O
35	B-DATE
years	I-DATE

in	O
N	B-GPE
.	I-GPE
E	I-GPE
.	I-GPE
Manchuria	I-GPE
a	O
country	O
as	O
large	O
as	O
France	B-GPE
;	O
and	O
in	O
the	O
South	B-LOC

the	O
tributary	O
states	O
of	O
Ann	O
am	O
,	O
which	O
is	O
now	O
larger	O
than	O
France	B-GPE
,	O
and	O

Burma	B-GPE
have	O
passed	O
from	O
her	O
control	O
.	O

For	O
lack	O
of	O
commercial	O
knowledge	O
she	O
has	O
80	B-MONEY
millions	I-MONEY
sterling	I-MONEY
less	O

foreign	O
trade	O
annually	O
than	O
India	B-GPE
,	O
she	O
only	O
doubles	O
her	O
trade	O
during	O

the	O
same	O
time	O
as	O
Japan	B-GPE
trebles	O
hers	O
,	O
her	O
tea	B-PRODUCT
trade	O
rapidly	O
declines	O
for	O

want	O
of	O
adaptation	O
to	O
the	O
changing	O
needs	O
of	O
the	O
market	O
.	O
Her	O
banking	O

commission	O
for	O
transfer	O
of	O
money	O
from	O
one	O
part	O
of	O
the	O
country	O
to	O

another	O
is	O
enormously	O
high	O
,	O
and	O
a	O
million	B-CARDINAL
people	O
are	O
daily	O
engaged	O
in	O

the	O
primitive	O
way	O
of	O
weighing	O
their	O
silver	B-PRODUCT
and	O
counting	O
their	O
cash	O
.	O

For	O
lack	O
of	O
economical	O
means	O
of	O
transport	O
,	O
China	B-GPE
fails	O
to	O
obtain	O
the	O

enormous	O
benefits	O
which	O
the	O
West	B-LOC
reaps	O
from	O
this	O
source	O
.	O
Mulihall	O

estimates	O
the	O
annual	O
gain	O
to	O
Europe	B-LOC
from	O
railways	O
alone	O
at	O
no	O
less	O
than	O

1,200	B-MONEY
millions	I-MONEY
sterling	I-MONEY
!	O
As	O
the	O
Chinese	B-GPE
Empire	I-GPE
is	O
in	O
area	O
and	O
popula	O
¬	O

tion	O
about	O
the	O
same	O
as	O
Europe	B-LOC
,	O
what	O
she	O
misses	O
for	O
want	O
of	O
these	O
is	O

evidently	O
immense	O
.	O

For	O
lack	O
of	O
scientific	O
and	O
engineering	O
training	O
the	O
many	O
millions	B-MONEY

of	I-MONEY
pounds	I-MONEY
sterling	O
which	O
each	O
nation	O
in	O
the	O
West	B-LOC
gains	O
annually	O
from	O

these	O
,	O
are	O
not	O
within	O
the	O
reach	O
of	O
any	O
educated	O
Chinamen	B-NORP
as	O
yet	O
.	O

For	O
lack	O
of	O
sound	O
knowledge	O
in	O
practical	O
philanthropy	O
among	O
her	O

very	O
numerous	O
religious	O
teachers	O
—	O
priests	B-NORP
and	O
nuns	B-NORP
—	O
the	O
great	O
benefit	O

that	O
might	O
be	O
derived	O
from	O
such	O
a	O
large	O
number	O
is	O
not	O
reaped	O
.	O

The	O
result	O
of	O
general	O
ignorance	O
on	O
such	O
lines	O
as	O
indicated	O
is	O
the	O

great	O
poverty	O
of	O
the	O
nation	B-LOC
as	O
a	O
whole	O
.	O
While	O
many	O
are	O
rich	O
,	O
the	O
great	O

mass	O
is	O
in	O
terrible	O
poverty	O
.	O
The	O
poor	O
,	O
again	O
,	O
have	O
to	O
pay	O
36	B-PERCENT
per	I-PERCENT
cent	I-PERCENT
,	O

to	O
pawnshops	O
,	O
and	O
1	B-PERCENT
U	I-PERCENT
0	I-PERCENT
per	I-PERCENT
cent	I-PERCENT
,	O
often	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
tide	O
over	O
temporary	O

difficulties	O
.	O
Thousands	O
upon	O
thousands	O
collect	O
in	O
mat	O
sheds	O
at	O
every	O

great	O
city	O
in	O
the	O
winter	O
in	O
order	O
to	O
attend	O
the	O
free	O
soup	O
kitchens	O
there	O
.	O

This	O
practically	O
amounts	O
to	O
slow	O
starvation	O
.	O
Thus	O
China	B-GPE
presents	O
such	O

an	O
amount	O
of	O
suffering	O
as	O
far	O
surpasses	O
that	O
of	O
any	O
other	O
country	O
.	O
Yet	O

most	O
of	O
it	O
might	O
be	O
easily	O
removed	O
.	O

#	O
#	O
p	O
.	O
(	O
#	O
3	O
)	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O

5	O

-	O
c	O
:	O
o	O
<	O
H	O
<	O
oH	O
*	O
o	O
:	O
o	O
-	O

1892-93	B-DATE

PRESIDENT	O
:	O

Sir	B-PERSON
ROBERT	I-PERSON
HART	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
G	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
C	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
M	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
G	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON

VICE	O
-	O
PRESIDENT	O
:	O

JOHN	B-PERSON
G	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
PURDON	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON

ORDINARY	O
DIRECTORS	O
:	O

Rev	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Y	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
J	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Allen	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
D	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
D	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
LL	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
D	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON

F	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
C	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Bishop	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

J	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
C	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Bois	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON

R	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
E	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Bredon	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

Andrew	B-PERSON
Burman	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

R	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
M	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Campbell	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

W	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
R	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Carles	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

C	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Cromie	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

G	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Detring	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

G	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
B	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Dodwell	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

E	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
B	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Drew	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

W	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
V	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Drummond	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

Rev	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Dr	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Edkins	I-PERSON
.	O

Wade	B-PERSON
Gard	I-PERSON
’	I-PERSON
ner	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

N	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
J	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Hannen	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

H	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
R	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Hearn	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

Dr	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
E	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Henderson	I-PERSON
.	O

H	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
M	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Hillier	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

H	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
E	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Hobson	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

Rev	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
H	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
C	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Hodges	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
M	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
A	I-PERSON
.	O

George	B-PERSON
Jamieson	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

Carl	B-PERSON
Jantzen	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

H	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
H	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Joseph	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

James	B-PERSON
J	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Keswick	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

J	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
A	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Leonard	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

R	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
W	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Little	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

Rev	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
H	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
H	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Lowry	I-PERSON
.	O

Rev	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
W	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
A	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
P	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Martin	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
D	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
D	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
LL	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
D	I-PERSON
.	O

John	B-PERSON
Macgregor	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

E	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
McKean	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

O	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Messing	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

The	B-PERSON
Yen	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Archdeacon	I-PERSON
Moule	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
B	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
D	I-PERSON
.	O

Rev	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
William	I-PERSON
Muirhead	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
B	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
A	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON

W	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
N	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Pethick	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON

G	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
M	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
H	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Playfair	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON

J	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
G	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Purdon	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

John	B-PERSON
Seaman	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

Herbert	B-PERSON
Smith	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

J	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
L	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Scott	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

N	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
A	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Siebs	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

Rev	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
John	I-PERSON
Stevens	I-PERSON
.	O

Rev	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
J	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
W	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Stevenson	I-PERSON
.	O

W	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
H	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Talbot	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

Cornelius	B-PERSON
Thorne	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

Rev	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Dr	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Wheeler	I-PERSON
.	O

E	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
H	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Wheeley	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

TRUSTEES	B-ORG
:	O

John	B-PERSON
Macgregor	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
J	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
K	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Morrison	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
R	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
M	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Campbell	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

HONORARY	O
TREASURER	O
:	O

W	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
H	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
POATE	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

HONORARY	O
SECRETARY	O
.	O
—	O
Rev	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
TIMOTHY	I-PERSON
RICHARD	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON

EXECUTIVE	B-ORG
COMMITTEE	I-ORG
:	O

Rev	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Dr	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Y	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
J	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Allen	I-PERSON

Rev	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Dr	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Edkins	I-PERSON
.	O

W	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
H	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Poate	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

Rev	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
W	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Muirhead	I-PERSON
.	O

John	B-PERSON
G	I-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Purdon	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

C	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Thorne	I-PERSON
,	I-PERSON
Esq	I-PERSON
.	O

Rev	B-PERSON
.	I-PERSON
Timothy	I-PERSON
Richard	I-PERSON
.	O

#	O
#	O
p	O
.	O
(	O
#	O
8	O
)	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O
#	O

10	O

Some	O
of	O
the	O
most	O
enlightened	O
Chinamen	B-NORP
who	O
read	O
our	O
Periodicals	B-PRODUCT

regularly	O
,	O
see	O
this	O
and	O
know	O
some	O
of	O
the	O
remedies	O
to	O
he	O
applied	O
.	O

Railways	B-FAC
are	O
now	O
sanctioned	O
to	O
be	O
worked	O
in	O
Tientsin	B-GPE
:	O
cotton	B-PRODUCT
factories	B-FAC

and	O
steel	B-PRODUCT
works	O
are	O
introduced	O
in	O
Shanghai	B-GPE
and	O
Hankow	B-GPE
,	O
so	O
that	O
the	O

people	O
of	O
China	O
may	O
partake	O
of	O
their	O
benefits	O
.	O
But	O
the	O
remedies	O
are	O

very	O
slow	O
in	O
their	O
application	O
,	O
and	O
the	O
great	O
bulk	O
of	O
even	O
the	O
mandarins	B-NORP

are	O
not	O
only	O
utterly	O
ignorant	O
of	O
their	O
being	O
the	O
greatest	O
sufferers	O
on	O

earth	B-LOC
,	O
but	O
complacently	O
congratulate	O
each	O
other	O
that	O
they	O
belong	O
to	O
the	O

only	O
Celestial	B-LOC
Empire	I-LOC
on	O
earth	O
!	O
Few	O
among	O
them	O
suspect	O
that	O
our	O

little	O
Society	B-ORG
possesses	O
the	O
knowledge	O
by	O
which	O
these	O
gigantic	O
evils	O
—	O

material	O
,	O
moral	O
and	O
spiritual	O
—	O
can	O
be	O
remedied	O
.	O
But	O
we	O
do	O
know	O
the	O

remedies	O
,	O
and	O
by	O
organized	O
efforts	O
we	O
are	O
determined	O
to	O
make	O
them	O

known	O
throughout	O
every	O
corner	O
of	O
this	O
vast	O
Empire	B-LOC
.	O
Some	O
day	O
those	O

who	O
read	O
our	O
periodic	O
and	O
systematic	O
treatment	O
of	O
their	O
ills	O
,	O
will	O
,	O
in	O

China	B-GPE
as	O
elsewhere	O
,	O
understand	O
our	O
motives	O
and	O
bless	O
us	O
for	O
our	O
work	O
.	O

Meanwhile	O
we	O
have	O
the	O
conviction	O
that	O
by	O
helping	O
the	O
Chinese	B-NORP
who	O
are	O

in	O
need	O
of	O
enlightenment	O
,	O
we	O
are	O
helping	O
to	O
lessen	O
the	O
sum	O
total	O
of	O

suffering	O
from	O
the	O
face	O
of	O
the	O
earth	B-LOC
,	O
we	O
are	O
opening	O
the	O
way	O
for	O

development	O
on	O
all	O
sides	O
in	O
every	O
province	B-LOC
,	O
and	O
greatly	O
strengthening	O

the	O
hands	O
of	O
all	O
the	O
best	O
in	O
the	O
land	O
.	O
The	O
grand	O
record	O
of	O
history	O

which	O
the	O
Chinese	B-NORP
possess	O
in	O
the	O
past	O
is	O
assurance	O
of	O
a	O
glorious	O
future	O

for	O
them	O
.	O
It	O
is	O
our	O
privilege	O
to	O
be	O
of	O
service	O
to	O
them	O
in	O
this	O
their	O
hour	O

of	O
great	O
need	O
,	O
and	O
to	O
give	O
them	O
the	O
advice	O
of	O
true	O
friends	O
.	O

